Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
SHIN SEIKI
''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
I wonder if he's going to play hooky again today.
Shin-chan's room.
Shinji, get up ! Why do
you keep skipping school ?!
It's been five days.
Unit 01 is completely repaired.
You're the pilot, how can
you leave it that way ?
Shinji ?
He's run away......
That's not surprising.
EPISODE 4:
Rain,
After He
Ran Away.
Shinji...?!
Um, we're...
We're Ikari Shinji's classmates,
Aida and Suzuhara.
Aida and Suzuhara ?
Yes.
I'm Suzuhara.
If I'm not mistaken, you're the ones who got into Unit 01's entry plug ?
We're very sorry for causing you so much trouble the other day.
Ikari has been absent from school since then, so we just came to see if he's okay.
Shinji. He's at Nerv's
training center right now.
Oh, I see.
Here are the prints which
were piled on his desk.
Sorry for all the trouble.
Thank you.
Well, please excuse us.
Please say hello
to Shinji for us.
Yes, I will. Bye.
This's an
unexpected development.
She's beautiful,
isn't she ?
Shinji, you damned fool !
Idiot !
Exit on the right side
at the next station.
Thank you very much for taking Tokyo-3's Loop Line 7 today.
This train will be out
of service at this station.
Everyone, please check to be sure you don't forget any of your belongings when you exit.
I have to go back.
Didn't you detect it ?
No. An object with a diameter
of tens of millimeters...
...hit Antarctica at
ten percent of light speed.
With our scientific knowledge, we could neither detect nor prevent it.
It's hell on earth outside.
What does science exist for ?!
At present, the atmosphere flow caused by the Earth's axis transition has decreased 3%.
Has it calmed
down at all ?
No. A tidal wave's approaching at a speed of 230 meters/second.
Doctor, let's escape.
I have an obligation
to stay here.
Doctor, it's easy to die, but you have an obligation to watch this hellish world...
Idiot.
He's only
14 years old.
In the end, it seems so cruel for him to be burdened with humanity's destiny.
But we must entrust the piloting of the Evas to the hands of 14 year old children.
I know.
So, have you
heard from him ?
Nothing ?
Nothing.
He might not come back.
What are you
going to do ?
Nothing special.
If he doesn't come back,
it might be better for him.
Why ?
After the last battle...
Why did you
ignore my orders ?
I'm sorry.
I'm your commander
in the operation, right ?
Yes.
You have an obligation to obey my orders. Do you understand ?
Make this the last time.
Yes.
Do you really understand
what I'm saying ?
Yes.
Hey, it won't be all right if you answer only ``yes'' to everything vaguely.
I understand well, of course. That's enough, isn't it ? We won anyway.
As long as you go along with what others want ostensibly, you may feel comfortable.
But if you continue to get into Eva with such a feeling, you'll be killed.
I wouldn't mind.
I wish I could
say you're resolute...
...but you're making a big mistake if you think you'll be praised by me, Ikari Shinji.
That isn't the question. Anyhow, I'm the only one who can pilot it.
I'll do it.
I see.
If it's only pain for him to pilot Eva,
then he shouldn't do it.
I'm sure he'll be killed.
But we need pilots.
Captain !
A...Aida, go ahead !
I can't go without you.
You fool !
Transferee !
Ikari !
NEON GENESIS
Touji's sorry about that.
He said that he'd been
scolded by his younger sister.
She told him that it was the robot that saved our lives.
It's shameful that he was scolded by a primary schooler, wasn't it ?
I like night because the
cicadas don't make loud noises.
Although, their number
has been growing in recent years.
Misato said that the ecosystems are returning to their former states.
Misato...I envy you. You live with such a beautiful lady and can pilot Evangelion.
If I could pilot it just once,
my heart would be content.
You'd better not. I think your mother would be worried.
Ah, it's O.K.
I don't have one.
I'm the same as you.
You'll eat, won't you ?
Yeah.
Do you do this
kind of thing often ?
Well, sort of...
Is it training for
guerrilla warfare ?
What could I do with toys like these ?~~I just like to.
You're Ikari Shinji,
aren't you ?
Yes.
We're from
Nerv Security Intelligence.
According to the eighth clause of
Public Security Regulations...
...we're taking you
to headquarters. Alright ?
Okay.
Then, you just watched ?!
That's easy for you to say, but like I said, they were pros from Nerv Security Intelligence.
So what ?! I can't believe
you don't have any balls !
Disgusting.
Pervert.
Haru !
The one who fights without any chance of winning is a fool.
It's got nothing
to do with balls.
It's been a while.
Yes.
Bumming around for two days...
Did it cheer you up ?
Not really.
Eva is ready.
Are you going to pilot it...?
...or aren't you ?
You won't scold me, will you ?
That's natural, because
you're not my relative.
If I tell you that I don't want to pilot Unit 01, how will you deal with it ?
I think Rei will pilot it.
Won't you pilot it ?
It seems unrealistic that
you'd force it all off on her.
Don't worry,
I'll pilot it.
You don't want to,
do you ?
Of course not. First of all,
I'm not cut out for it.
But Ayanami,
you and Ritsuko...
Knock it off already !
It's got nothing to do
with what others say !
If you don't want to
pilot it, then leave !
Forget about Eva and us completely !
Go back to where you came from !
It's wrong for you to
pilot it with such feelings.
The ``Third Child'' is
leaving Tokyo-3 tomorrow.
Then we'll reconfigure the
data of Unit 01 for Rei.
But...
Regardless of the data from
Unit 00's restart experiment...
...we'll resume
with Unit 01.
According to the
Marduk Organization's report...
...the ``Fourth Child''
hasn't been found yet.
You mean that we don't
have anyone to substitute ?
Wh...where's Misato ?
I'd like to say good-bye.
You don't belong to Nerv now, so I can't tell you anything.
Ikari, you forgot this !
Uh, can I have
a little time ?
Um...thank you.
Touji, say it ! Come on !
Ikari, I'm sorry that I punched you twice. Hit me, please !
I can't do that.
Please. Otherwise,
I won't be satisfied.
Well, he's an
embarrassing guy like this.
If it'll settle this,
why not ?
But...
Be quick ! You don't
have time, right ?
Only once, then.
Okay !
Come on !
Stop !
Don't hold back !
How did you know...?
It was a hunch. We've seen dozens of classmates off lately.
If you leave, we'll also have
to leave this city some day.
But we don't have the right to say anything about that. We saw you suffering in the Eva.
If I find someone
who blames you...
...I'll beat the
crap out of him !
Don't make such
a gloomy face.
Cheer up.
Hang in there.
I'm...
Time's up.
I'm the one who
needed to be hit !
I'm a coward,
I'm timid...
...dishonest and
a weakling...
Don't give us
any more trouble.
He's gone.
Do you think
this is best ?
The hedgehog's dilemma...
The closer they get, the more deeply they hurt each other...
I've figured out
what it means.
He can't let others know his feelings in any other way than that.
A linear express train for Atsugi is arriving on Track 2.
Be careful and stand
behind the yellow line.
The train on Track 2 is a special train exclusively for government use.
General passengers are not permitted to enter within the fences.
Anyone without authorization is firmly prohibited from boarding.
Hang in there.
Look.
It's that babe.
A local train for Gora
is arriving on Track 4 soon.
Be careful and stand
behind the yellow line.
If you are accompanied by small children, pay attention to them, please.
The train on Track 4 is the local one which is turning back for Gora.
If you take this train,
please wait inside.
The train is arriving soon.
Please stand behind the yellow line.
I...I'm back.
Welcome home.
TO BE CONTINUED
~~Shinji: Megumi Ogata
Misato Katsuragi: Kotono Mitsuishi~~~~
Ritsuko Akagi: Yuriko Yamagushi~
Gendou Ikari: Fumihiko Tachiki
Touji Suzuhara: Tomokazu Seki~~~
~Kensuke Aida: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Announcer: Hiro Yuuki~
Announcer: Megumi Hayashibara
Couple: Kouichi Nagano~
~~~~~~~Yuuko Miyamura
Initial Translation
Wada Mitsuhito
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Hiroaki Fukuda
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Ayanami Rei lives with
minimal contact with others.
Shinji is at a loss to see this girl who's closer to his father than he.
Before the wound in
his heart heals up...
...the light from an Angel
burns the chest of Eva Unit 01.
The next episode:
Rei, Beyond Her Heart