Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
NEON GENESIS
Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
Nerv Headquarters -- Experiment Station-02
22 days earlier.
Activate.
Connect main power
supply to all circuits.
Main power supply connected.
Activation system operating.
Operational voltage,
critical point in...0.5, 0.2...
It's reached.
Move on to the second phase
of the activation system.
The pilot's
commencing connection.
Start System Phase II.
Synapses inserted.
Connection started.
Pulses transmitted.
All circuits are normal.
Initial contact;
no problems.
Send power to
both brachial muscles.
All nerve links;
no problems.
Checklist cleared
up to 2550.
Arrange for the
third connection.
Up to 2580 cleared.
Absolute borderline in...
...pulses are
flowing back !
Troubles occurring
in the third phase.
Rejection is setting into
the central nerve elements.
Stop the contacts.
Release the circuits up to No.6.
I can't !
It's not receiving the signals !
Unit 00 is out of control !
Abort the experiment.
Turn off the power supply.
Yes, sir !
Unit 00 has switched
to back-up power.
Thirty-five seconds
til complete shutdown.
It's dangerous !
Step back !
Auto ejection has been initiated !
No !
Complete
shutdown in...
Special Bakelite !
Hurry !
Rei !
Rei, are you all right ?
Rei ?!
Good.
Episode 5
Rei,
Beyond Her Heart
Ayanami Rei, 14 years old....
...the so called ``First Child'' is the first testee discovered based on the Marduk Report.
She's the exclusive pilot
of Evangelion Prototype Unit 00.
Her personal history was started anew and all her records were already erased.
Well, what was the cause of the accident during the last experiment ?
It's still unknown.
But the primary cause is thought to be a mental instability in the pilot.
Mental instability ?
In Rei ?
Yes. She was disturbed much
more than we had thought.
What happened ?
I don't know.
But she might have ...
Do you have any ideas ?
No, that can't be...
Demolition of
Block-D3 completed.
Please submit all data to Analyzing Group of 1st Division, Engineering Bureau.
This is our enemy,
isn't it  ?
I see. It retains the
original form except its core.
This is truly an ideal sample.
I really appreciate it.
Well, did you
find something ?
What's this ?
It's the code number,
meaning insolubility.
In other words, you don't
know anything at all, do you ?
No.
The Angel is composed of matter which has the properties of both particle and wave, like light.
Well, you found its
power source, didn't you ?
Something like that. But I've got nothing on its working mechanisms.
We only confirmed that there're so many unknowns in this world, right  ?
Anyway, the world
is full of mysteries.
For example, look at this particular wave pattern of the Angel.
Let me see.
This is...
Yes. Although the constituent elements are different...
...the arrangement and coordinates of the signals are very similar to that of humans.
Around 99.89%.
99.89% means...
This reveals how limited
our intelligence is.
OK. All right.
Stop !
This is the core...
What about the rest ?
Degradation is very serious. It has too many problems to be used as a sample.
That's alright. Throw away
all the other parts.
Yes, sir.
What's the matter ?
Um...no...nothing special.
Listen, when you say ``Nothing,'' with such a face...
...you look to me like you're saying ``Think about me. Please, worry about me.''
Well, Father seems to have
gotten a burn on his hand.
Burn ?
I wonder what
happened to him.
Burn...Do you
know about that ?
Before you arrived, Unit 00 went out of control during the activation experiment.
You've heard about it,
haven't you  ?
Yes.
The pilot was locked
inside at that time.
The pilot was Ayanami,
wasn't it ?
Commander Ikari helped her get out.
He forced the overheated hatch open.
Father did...
That was when he got
the burn on his palm.
Go for it, Hideko !
Now, let's sink a shot !
Alright !
All the chicks got
gorgeous breasts.
Somehow Suzuhara's
eyes look indecent.
Hey, sir ! What are you
looking at so eagerly ?
Er, nothing particularly.
Ayanami, by any chance ?
N...no.
Oh, c'mon.
You can't fool me.
Ayanami's bust, Ayanami's
thighs and Ayanami's...
...calves !
Like I said,
that's not it.
What were you
looking at, then ?
Don't try and
avoid the question.
Well, I was wondering
why she's always alone.
Come to think, she hasn't made any friends since she came here for first grade.
I don't know why, but everyone
thinks she's unapproachable.
The truth is, she might
have a bad attitude.
Both of you are
Eva pilots, right ?
So you know more about her than the rest of us, don't you ?
That's right.
We hardly speak
to each other.
Eva Unit 01 will be in
the third cooling phase.
Please shut down all systems
of Cage 06 up to phase 3.
No problems with the last harmonics and synchronization tests.
All numerical
conditions satisfied.
Roger. Report the
results to Balthazar.
Roger.
Copy the personal data of the entry plug to Melchior in all ranges. I'm sending the data.
Melchior, roger.
Circuits connected.
The third cooling
phase is starting.
CBL circulation is started.
Send the wastewater to the
second water purification system.
The conditions of all
protein walls are normal.
Minus 1,050 minutes until
Unit 00 reactivation experiment.
What's this ?!
Curry.
You're eating
instant, as usual.
You've been invited to dinner,
so you shouldn't complain !
Misato ?
Oh, me...
Ta da.
Put it into this.
Are you serious ?
Why not ?
This is very good.
Alright...
You can't have this kind of taste with a curry-flavored cup'a'noodle.
I'll help myself.
It's a knack to keep the soup base and hot water less than usual.
Misato cooked this,
didn't she ?
Yes.
Oh, you noticed ?
From the taste.
How could she
mess up instant food...?
If you invite me again, please call me on the day Shinji's cooking.
Shinji, you'd better move.
You shouldn't spoil your life under the influence of a rude roommate.
I've gotten used to it.
He's right, Ritsuko. Don't underestimate a human's ability to adapt to its environment.
Besides, if he moves...
Oh...Shinji,
one more, please.
Okay.
He'd have to follow
troublesome procedures.
Shinji's only got the
formal security card, you know ?
Oh, I nearly forgot.
Shinji, I have a favor to ask you.
What is it ?
Ayanami Rei's new card.
I missed the chance
to give it to her.
I'm sorry, but could you deliver it to her home on your way to headquarters ?
Sure.
What's the matter ? You're looking at Rei's photo very intently.
Ah...no.
Shin, could you be... ?
No !
Come on.
You look so embarrassed.
You've got an official excuse to go to Rei's home. It's a nice chance, right ?
Stop teasing me !
You're worth teasing
because of your quick temper.
Just like Misato.
I just thought that I know so little about her, even though we're both the pilots of Eva...
She's a good girl, and like your father,
she isn't good at it, though.
She isn't good at...
What ?
Living.
NEON GENESIS
Excuse me.
Excuse me. It's Ikari.
Ayanami, I'm coming in.
Are these Ayanami's...?
I, um...
I didn't really...
Won't you move ?
I...um...
What is it ?
Well, I...
I...was...asked...
I mean...What was that...?
The card, the card...
Your card's been renewed, and I was asked to bring it to you.
So, that's why...
I wasn't going to do...
Ritsuko told me that she'd
forgotten to give it to you.
It's true. But no one answered when I rung the doorbell and the door was unlocked...
Central Dogma is open now.
Please use the 4th entry gate.
Here's the new one
Ritsuko asked me to bring.
I'm sorry about that.
About what ?
Well, I heard that you're going to try the reactivation experiment today.
I hope it'll be
successful this time.
Say, aren't you afraid of getting into that Unit 00 again ?
Why ?
I heard that you were injured during the last experiment, so I wondered if you felt alright.
You're Commander Ikari's son,
aren't you ?
Yes.
Don't you trust
your father's work ?
Of course not.
Not from a father like him.
Um...
Rei, are you
all right ? Rei !
The pilot was locked
inside at that time.
Commander Ikari helped her get out.
He forced the overheated hatch open.
That's when he got
the burn on his palm.
Rei, can you hear me ?
Yes.
We're going to try reactivating Unit 00.
Start the first connection.
Connect main
power supply.
Voltage has exceeded
the critical point.
Roger. Move the
format to Phase II.
The pilot's
connecting to Unit 00.
The circuits are opening.
The conditions of pulses
and harmonics are normal.
There are no problems
with synchronization.
All nerve links are finished.
Nerve center devices are operational.
No error in
recalculated tolerances.
Checklist,
up to 2590, cleared.
Absolute critical line in...
0.1.
It's passed.
Borderline cleared.
Unit 00 has activated.
Roger. I'll start an
interlocking test without a break.
Ikari, an unidentified object's approaching.
I think it's the fifth Angel.
Interrupt the test.
All hands on first class alert.
Why don't you
use Unit 00 ?
It's not ready for combat yet.
How's Unit 01 ?
It'll take 380 seconds
to prepare it.
Move it out.
Aye, sir.
Rei, we succeeded in
reactivating. Come back.
The target has
flown over Tonosawa.
Unit 01 begin
preparations for launch.
Release the first lock bolt.
Release confirmed.
Roger. Release the
second binding.
Roger.
The target has arrived in the area over Lake Ashino.
Eva Unit 01 is
ready for launch.
Launch !
A powerful energy reaction
detected inside the target !
What ?!
Accelerating to its outer
rim and converging.
Could it be...?!
No, get out of the way !
Shinji !
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Kouzou: Genmu Kiyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
~~~~Men: Hitoshi Yamanoi
~~~~~~~~Kouichi Nagano
Announcer: Yuuko Miyamura~~~
Initial Translation
Kentaro Onizuka
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Shinji was saved.
But the wound
makes him babble.
Rei gives him
the cold shoulder.
Will Shinji's hope and power from all over Japan be able to pierce through the Angel ?
Next time:
``The Decisive Battle in Tokyo-3.''