Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
SHIN SEIKI
''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
A powerful energy reaction
detected inside the target.
What ?!
Accelerating to its
outer rim and converging.
Could it be...?!
No, get out
of the way !
Recover it, quickly !
Target is silent.
What about Shinji ?
He's alive.
Unit 01 recovered.
Move to 7th cage.
I'm going to the cage.
Take care of the rest.
Unit 01 secured.
Pilot's brainwaves unstable.
Pulse very weak.
Life support system full.
Begin heart massage.
Alright.
Pulse confirmed.
Eject the plug forcefully, hurry !
LCL emergency exhaust.
Roger.
Hurry, open the hatch.
Quickly !
Shinji...
Episode 6:
Decisive Battle
in Tokyo-3.
Scale: 1/1 Balloon Dummy
Struck by the enemy particle
accelerator cannon. Dummy evaporated.
Next.
Type-12 Automatic Cannon
Type-12 Automatic
Cannon destroyed.
I see.
According to the data
we've collected so far...
...it's presumed that the enemy automatically attacks any target inside a certain range.
100% of the targets inside that area have been destroyed by the particle cannon.
Close range combat
with Eva is too risky.
What about its AT-field ?
Still active. It's so strong that we can even see the phase-shifted space.
Pathetic attacks like inductive cannons or bombing are a waste.
Defense and offense almost perfect.
It's like a floating fortress.
Then, what about
that troublesome probe ?
The target is directly above us, entering Tokyo-3 area Zero.
A gigantic probe with a diameter of 17.5 meters is drilling into Nerv HQ, in the Geo-Front.
The enemy is going to attack Nerv HQ directly, I suppose.
How corny.
And what's the estimated
time of penetration ?
At six minutes fifty-four
seconds after midnight.
At that time, we estimate
it will reach the Nerv HQ...
...after breaking through
all 22 defense barriers.
Less than 10 hours left...
Enemy probe has reached
the first defense barrier.
What's the condition
of Unit 01 ?
Chest piece, third defense armor,
was heavily melted.
It was fortunate that the
central control unit stayed intact.
Three more seconds,
and it'd have been ``out.''
Replacement will be
completed in 3 hours.
Roger.
What about Unit 00 ?
No problem with restarting, but errors are still detected in its feedback.
An actual battle is...
...still impossible...? What's the condition of Unit 01's pilot ?
No physical damage. Nerve pulse's are 0.8 higher than normal, but it's acceptable.
9 hours 55 minutes
to enemy penetration.
The situation
isn't so good.
Should we wave
a flag of truce ?
I have one tiny thing
to try before that.
Long range direct fire from outside the target's range ?
Yes. There's no other way but to break through one point...
...with the high energy condenser without neutralizing its AT-field.
What did Magi say ?
Super computer Magi's answer
is two for affirmative...
...one for affirmative,
with some conditions.
Chance of winning is 8.7%.
That's the highest value.
There's no reason to reject it.
Carry on, Captain Katsuragi.
Aye, sir.
Anyway, you've planned an absurd operation, Miss Planning Manager Katsuragi.
``Absurd?'' You're so rude. It can be done in 9 hours, and it's the most effective plan.
Is this...really ?
Eva Special Positron Rifle
(Cyclotron prototype 20)
Our positron rifle won't be able to withstand that much power.
What are you
going to do ?
It's obvious. I'm going
to borrow another one.
``Borrow ?''
You mean...
Yep. The SSDF(Strategic Self
Defense Force) Lab's prototype.
For those reasons,
Special Institute, Nerv...
...has the right to requistion this automatic positron cannon as of 15:00 today.
But, you know...
It's impossible.
We'll do our best to return this in its original condition.
Well, thank you very
much for your cooperation.
Okay Rei, take it out.
This is a delicate machine,
so handle with care.
But, the power to defeat an AT-field is at least 180 million kilowatts.
Where are you going
to find that much power ?
It's obvious.
From all over Japan.
Sorry for interrupting the program,
but we have emergency news.
From 11:30 pm today, through early morning tomorrow, a large scale...
...blackout's planned for all of Japan. We thank you for your cooperation.
I repeat. From 11:30 pm today,
through early morning tomorrow...
...a large scale blackout's planned for all of Japan. We thank you for your cooperation.
Enemy probe has broken
through 7th defense barrier.
What's the status of the
energy supply system ?
3.2% delay from the plan at this moment, but we'll complete it by 23:10 today.
How's the positron rifle ?
For the honor of Tech Development Section 3, we'll build it in 3 hours.
What about the
defense method ?
Well, there's no other
way but to use a shield.
Is this a shield ?
Yes. It's a
hand-me-down from SSTO.
It doesn't look good, but the bottom part is super electromagnetically coated...
...so it should withstand that attack for 17 seconds. Section 2 guarantees that.
That's nice.
Where's the firing location ?
Considering the distance to the target, geographical features...
...and the power supply installation, this is the best location.
Looks good.
Okay, the firing location
is the top of Mt. Futagoyama.
The operation starts
at 00:00.00 tonight.
This operation is
called ``Yashima Operation.''
Roger.
So, the pilots are
the final problem.
The pilot of Unit 01's regained consciousness.
There's no problem in the checked values.
Okay, then proceed with
the operation as planned.
Roger.
Will he really
get into it again ?
Proceed to the final battle
on Mt. Futagoyama. Hurry !
Ayanami...
I've come to inform you of the schedule for the Yashima Operation which starts at midnight.
Ikari and Ayanami, come to
the cage at 17:30 today.
18:00, activate Unit 00
and Unit 01.
18:05, launch.
18:30, arrive at temporary base at Mt. Futagoyama, and wait for orders.
The operation
starts at midnight.
Here's a new one.
Don't come looking like
``that'' because you're groggy.
Sorry.
I've been saying that
a lot since yesterday.
Your meal.
I don't feel like eating.
We depart in one hour.
Do I have to
get into it again?
Yes, that's right.
I don't want to. You can say that because you haven't had any awful experiences inside it.
I don't want to have that kind of experience again.
Why don't you
stay in bed ?
Stay in bed ?
I'll pilot Unit 01.
Dr. Akagi is ready to rewrite
the personal data of Unit 01.
Ritsuko is...?
Then, I'm going. Capt. Katsuragi
and Dr. Akagi are waiting for me.
Goodbye.
NEON GENESIS
I'm tired of waiting.
It's time to take shelter.
I peeked at my dad's data.
I'm sure about the time.
But they haven't shown up.
That mountain's moving.
It's Evangelion !
Awesome !
Good luck !
We all trust in you !
Enemy probe has broken through the 17th defense barrier.
3 hours 55 minutes
to arrival at HQ.
Electric power supply from Shikoku and Kyushu Areas complete.
Begin testing
each cooling system.
This's a delicate machine,
so handle with care.
This's only for a battlefield.
Will it really work ?
There's no other way.
It's an emergency.
Will it be alright ?
Theoretically, yes.
But I won't know if the barrel and accelerator can handle it until the first shot's fired.
We've never done any tests
with so much power.
I'll now announce each of
your positions in the operation.
Shinji.
Yes.
You're the
gunner in Unit 01.
Okay.
Rei, you're the
defense in Unit 00.
Yes, ma'am.
This is because Shinji's
synchronization ratio is higher.
This time,
we need precision.
Since the positron is affected by the rotation, magnetic field...
...and gravity of Earth,
it does not go straight.
Don't forget to adjust for that error.
You must hit the core precisely.
But, I've never practiced.
No problem.
Just do as the textbook says.
When the markers are aligned in the middle, pull the trigger.
The machine'll do
the rest automatically.
And it'll take a while for
the next shot because of...
...cooling, reloading,
and exchanging of the fuses.
Then, what if I miss, and the enemy starts shooting at us...?
Don't think about anything but hitting and destroying it with one shot.
We'd be in
big trouble, then.
I...I'll have to
protect Unit 01, right ?
Yes.
I understand.
It's time.
Change your clothes.
Okay.
We may die.
Why do you say that ?
You won't die...
...because I will protect you.
Why do you pilot it ?
Because of my ties.
Ties ?
Yes, ties.
With my father ?
With everyone.
You're strong, Ayanami.
I have nothing else.
``Nothing else ?''
It's time. Let's go.
Goodbye.
We're approaching midnight.
Start the operation.
Shinji, we entrust all the power of Japan to you. Do your best.
Okay.
Begin the first connection.
Sector 1 to 803,
start supplying power.
Voltage is coming up
to operational level.
All cooling systems,
full power.
Temperature stable.
No problems.
Positron charge, doing well.
Second connection.
Start all accelerators.
Start compulsive condenser.
Direct all power to the substation on Mt. Futagoyama. Third connection. No problems.
Release all final
safety systems.
Pull the bolt back.
Adjust for the gravity and rotation of the Earth. Plus 0.0009.
0.2 to firing voltage.
7th and final connection.
All energy to
the positron rifle.
5...
High energy reaction
detected in the target !
What ?!
1.
Fire !
Missed ?
Enemy probe has
reached the Geo-Front.
Hurry the second shot !
Exchanging fuses.
Start recharging.
Begin cooling the barrel.
High energy reaction detected
in the target again !
Damn it !
Shinji !
Ayanami !
The shield won't
be able to hold !
Not yet ?
10 more seconds !
Hurry !
Gotcha !
Ayanami !
Ayanami, are you alright ?!
Don't say,
``I have nothing else.''
Don't say a sad word
like ``goodbye'' when we go.
Why are you crying ?
Sorry, I don't know how to express myself in situations like this.
You should smile.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Kouzou: Genmu Kiyokawa~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~~
Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu~
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
~Staff: Kouichi Nagano
Announcer: Yuuko Miyamura~~~
Initial Translation
\C1Kentaro Onizuka
Additional Translation
and song translation
\C5Hiroaki Fukuda
\C1Editing
\C3Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
\C5Hiroaki Fukuda
Subtitled by
\C3Central Anime\C3(\C5Kansas\C3)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
A gigantic
humanoid weapon...
...developed by private companies went out of control during a test.
Will Misato be able to stop
the reactor from melting down ?
Next time: ``A Human Work.''