Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
NEON GENESIS
Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
Second and third Ashino Lakes...
I hope there's no more.
Chairman Keel complained to me directly about the delay of the project yesterday.
He was very frustrated.
He even mentioned dismissing you.
Adam's progressing smoothly. The Eva project has progressed to the dummy plug.
Why are those old
men of Seele so upset ?
And more importantly, the Human Complement Project's behind schedule.
All projects are mutually linked.
It'll be alright.
About Rei, also ?
Forget it.
By the way, what're you
going to do with ``him ?''
I'll leave him alone
just like Marduk Agency.
He's still useful for
a while longer, isn't he ?
Kyoto
What was begun here
sixteen years ago ?
Episode 15
A Lie and Silence
``uso to chinmoku''
It's me.
Oh, it's you.
Shanon Bio...
it's a foreign chemical company.
It was established here 9 years ago,
and it hasn't changed in 9 years.
106 out of 108 companies connected to the Marduk Agency are dummies.
And that's the 107th,
isn't it ?
This is the registration
of the company.
You're gonna say, ``Look at the names of the executive officers,'' right ?
So, you knew.
I already know
those names.
The Marduk Agency, which was established to choose the pilots for Evangelion...
...is an advisory organization under the Human Complement Committee's direct control.
Details of the organization
are still unknown.
Your duty is to investigate NERV. It's not advisable to meddle with the Organization.
Well, I won't be satisfied unless
I confirm everything myself.
Hello, this is Kaji. I'm out now.
Please leave a message if you need to.
Help me, Kaji !
What're you doing, you pervert ?!
That should do it.
What happened ?
Tomorrow's Sunday, and I wanted Kaji to take me somewhere, so I called him...
...but he's not there.
He's been out every time
I've called him these days.
That means you're
free tomorrow, right ?
Unfortunately, yes.
I want to ask
you a little favor.
Actually...
Date...?!
He's my sister Kodama's friend.
I was asked to introduce you.
I beg you.
Yo !
Do it seriously !
Sorry.
Cleaning is what you
should do seriously !
Necrosis procedure is over.
The reversible graph,
measuring complete.
What are you going
to wear tomorrow ?
For the wedding reception...?
I wore a pink suit
at Kiyomi's reception.
I just wore the deep
blue dress at Kotoko's.
What about the orange one ?
You haven't worn it for a while.
Oh, that one...?
I can't wear it for some reason...
Too tight ?
Damn right.
I'd better
buy a new one.
I've had to
spend a lot recently.
Lately, it's been happening one after another. The cost of gifts isn't going down either.
They must've rushed it
since they're almost thirty.
Neither you nor I want to be the last ones, do we ?
All three of you
can come back now.
Good work.
I'm tired of tests.
Come to think of it, Shinji looked depressed more than usual today.
Because ``it'' is tomorrow.
That's right,
``it'' is tomorrow.
I have to see
my father tomorrow.
What do you think
I should talk about ?
Why are you asking me ?
Because I've seen you
talking cheerfully to my father.
Can you tell me...what kind
of person is my father ?
I don't know.
I see.
Is that why you've been
staring at me, to ask that ?
At cleaning time you were wringing the dust cloth, weren't you ?
You looked motherly.
Mother ?
It looked like it was a
mother's way of wringing.
Actually, you may be suited
to being a housewife.
What are you
talking about ?
I'm home !
Welcome back.
Get to bed. You have a date tomorrow, don't you ?
Yeah, with a
``handsome'' guy.
Oh, that's right.
Can I use your lavender perfume ?
No.
You're stingy.
It's not for children.
Is Shinji in his room ?
He hasn't come out at all. He doesn't seem to want to see his father.
If he doesn't want to, why doesn't he say so ? Japanese are always...
It doesn't mean that he doesn't want to. And that's the problem.
Go home.
Good job, Shinji.
Shinji...
...I'm coming in.
Are you afraid of
seeing your father alone ?
You shouldn't
keep running away...
...but you have to step forward
or nothing'll change.
I know.
You'll discover the importance of going forward once you've taken the first step.
Anyway, be confident tomorrow.
You're going to see your mother as well.
Well, good night.
You bought a dress for tomorrow, right ?
Let me see it ?
You wanna see it ?
It was expensive.
Your sense is more
important than the price.
It's great.
Did you pick one
that Kaji would like ?
Well, I don't now.
The next day.
Well...
...we're...
...going.
Three bags in your heart...
Red, blue and yellow...
Well then, please take
some time to talk freely.
Ryo-chan hasn't showed up.
That idiot never
shows up on time.
For dating, right ?
He does when he's working.
Oh, you two are as
beautiful as ever.
I couldn't finish
my job in time.
Despite that, you're
always killing time ?
Besides, why're
you always unshaven ?
Hey, your tie's loose.
Oh, thanks.
You guys look like
a married couple.
I'm pleased to
hear that, Rit-chan.
Why would we be...?
It's been three years
since we visited here.
I ran away back then,
and I haven't come back until now.
I don't feel like
my mother's in there.
I don't remember
her face either.
People live by
forgetting the past.
But there are things
you shouldn't forget.
Yui taught me
that important fact.
I come here
to reaffirm that.
Don't you have any photos ?
No. This tombstone's ornamental.
There was no body.
You threw everything away, just like my teacher said, didn't you ?
Everything's inside my heart.
That's enough for now.
It's time.
I'm going back.
Father...
...well, I'm glad that
I could talk to you today.
I see.
NEON GENESIS
Not bad at all. I didn't know you could do stuff like that.
I can only play this well because I started when I was five...
...I don't have
much talent.
Don't they say, ``persistence is a virtue ?''
I have a better impression of you now.
I started playing because
my teacher suggested it.
I could have
given it up.
Then, why'd you
keep playing ?
Because no one
told me to stop.
I thought so.
You're home early. I thought
you were going to eat supper.
He was boring, so I left him while we were waiting for the roller coaster.
That's pretty rude.
Kaji's the only nice guy.
What're you talking about ?
I'm going to the bathroom.
Don't disappear.
High-heels...?
When was the last
time we drank together ?
Misato's been drinking too much.
She seems happy for some reason.
Drink to hide your cheerful self...
Today, I might be like that.
The person who lived with her
says something convincing.
We lived together, but that's before she put on high-heels.
We couldn't imagine that
when we were in school.
I was young, and we were simply staying in the same place. It was like playing house.
The reality isn't so sweet.
Oh, this is
for your cat.
Thanks.
You're so nice.
Only to women.
My work's sloppy.
I wonder.
To Misato, also ?
I bought a farm once. I won't join a losing war. That's my policy.
I think you have
a winning strategy.
What about you, Rit-chan ?
I have a policy not to talk about myself,
because it's not very interesting.
She's late. I wonder if
she's touching up her makeup.
Why did you
go to Kyoto ?
Hey, that's
from Matsushiro.
Don't play innocent. If you go too far, your fingers will get burned.
I'm giving you a warning,
as a friend.
I'll listen. It's okay if I get burned while I'm playing with you...
Should I buy you
some fireworks ?
Oh, welcome back.
Your fickle personality
hasn't changed at all.
Yes, it has.
To live is to change.
That's homeostasis
and transistasis.
What's that ?
The forces to maintain or
change the current situation.
We have both of those conflicting characteristics at the same time.
Like a man and woman.
I'd better go home.
I still have work to do.
Really ?
Too bad.
Bye.
Shin-chan...?
It's me.
I'm drinking with Kaji.
Yes, we're holding a third party.
Okay...okay...bye.
Misato ?
Yeah. She said she'll be late
and to go to bed.
She's not coming home
tomorrow morning, is she ?
She can't be because
Kaji's with her.
Are you stupid ?!
That's why I asked.
Grownups usually don't puke.
Sorry about being
old already.
We're the same age.
That's right.
You're wearing high-heels.
I really feel like time has passed.
Why don't you shave ?
Okay, okay.
I'll walk.  Thanks.
Kaji, have I changed ?
You've become more beautiful.
I'm sorry that I said
goodbye back then.
I told you I fell in love with another guy, but it was a lie. Did you know that ?
No.
I noticed that
you were like my father.
I was longing for
my father in men.
When I noticed that,
I was scared, so scared.
Staying with you, being a woman.
Everything was scary.
I hated my father, but I fell in love with a man like him.
I joined NERV
to forget everything.
But it's the organization my father once belonged to.
I was deceiving myself by
taking revenge against Angels.
You've chosen to do that.
You don't have to apologize to me.
No, I didn't choose !
I was simply running away.
I ran away from the
chains called ``father.''
It's just like Shinji.
I'm a coward.
I'm really sorry to say such things,
though it's because I'm drunk.
That's enough.
I'm so childish. I have no
right to preach to Shinji.
That's enough.
I'm hypocritical because I rely on a man at my convenience, just like now !
I might have used you back then !
I hate it !
That's enough. Stop.
I'm so disappointed
in myself !
Hey Shinji,
do you want to kiss ?
What ?
Kiss, you know, a kiss.
You haven't kissed, right ?
Then, let's do it.
Why ?
Because it's boring.
``Boring,'' you said...?
You don't want to kiss on the anniversary of your mom's death, do you ?
Do you think she might
be watching us from Heaven ?
No.
Are you scared ?
No, I'm not
scared of kissing.
You brushed your teeth,
didn't you ?
Then, here I come.
Don't breathe through
your nose, it tickles.
Yuck ! I shouldn't have done it
to kill time after all !
Hey, we're home.
Hang on.
Kaji.
Kaji !
Well, I'm going home.
Why don't you stay ?
They'll laugh at me if
I go to work looking like this.
It's okay.
Right, Kaji ?
See ya.
The smell of lavender...
You two, take care
of Katsuragi, okay ?
Okay.
Good night.
What's wrong ?
You look disappointed.
It's because I kissed you !
Well, girls are next.
Next day.
Ayanami...
Is Ayanami absent today, too ?
NERV Headquarters
The center of the deep
underground facilities.
Central Dogma
Same location.
2008 meters under ground.
Terminal Dogma
How's your hangover ?
It's gone, thanks to you.
That's good.
Is this your true job ?
Or just part time ?
I don't know.
Kaji Ryouji belongs to the Special Inspection Division of the Special Institute, NERV...
...but you also belong to Japan's Ministry of the Interior, don't you ?
You knew, huh ?
Don't underestimate NERV.
Did Commander Ikari order you ?
No, this's my own act.
If you continue your part time job any further, you'll die.
Commander Ikari's making use of me.
I'll continue for a while.
But I apologize to you
for keeping this a secret.
I'll cancel this to show
my thanks for last night.
Thanks. But the Commander, and even Rit-chan, kept this a secret from you.
This is it.
That's...
Eva...
No...it can't be.
Yes, it's the key to
everything since the Second Impact...
...and it was the
beginning as well.
It's Adam.
Adam...?
The First Angel is here...?!
Surely, NERV can't
be taken lightly.
TO BE CONTINUED
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
Version 1.0
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Woman: Miki Nagasawa
~~Host: Kouichi Nagano
Ikari Shinji finally surpasses Asuka, and scores the highest in the synchro test.
However, his overconfidence
draws him into Dirac's Ocean.
The limited time of survival
will teach him despair.
Next time:
``Deadly illness, then...''
Next time, service, service.