Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
SHIN SEIKI
''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
Shin-chan, did you
change the soup stock ?
Yeah, it's bonito.
It's a souvenir from Ritsuko.
Hot !
Sorry.
You apologized so easily !
Do you REALLY feel sorry ?!
Shinji, you always apologize as if it's a conditioned reflex to avoid criticism !
Sorry.
See ? You're so self-destructive,
to the core...
Now, now.
That's his lifestyle.
You're so naive giving
in to his lifestyle !
You're so understanding
towards Shinji lately !
Am I ?
Just because you restored
your relationship with Kaji...
...I don't want you to show
off how happy you are.
There's nothing
between Kaji and me.
Yo, Katsuragi. I found a bar with good liquor. How about tonight ? Bye.
I've never had such an
indecent adult relationship, like you !
What's with you ?!
You act just like a parent !
You're so hypocritical !
It's disgusting !
Deadly Illness,
Then...
''Shi ni
itaru yamai,
soshite''
Type B harmonics test, normal.
All depth parameters cleared.
Misato, you look tired.
Because of various
private reasons...
Kaji ?
Shut up !
How's the
Third Child doing ?
Look at this.
Let's see...
I hope this helps him gain
a little more confidence.
Can you hear me, Shinji ?
Misato, how was the
result from that test ?
Hi, kimi ga ichiban !
He's done it !
He surpassed me easily !
He did it so easily,
that to be honest, I'm irritated !
Great, wonderful,
strong, so strong !
Oh, unbeatable Shinji...
Our job'll be easier !
Right ?  We must work harder so we won't be left behind.
Bye.
Next stop is Seishoukaose,
Seishoukaose...
...in front of Bashohal's
used books and software...
Alright.
It'll take five more minutes to evacuate the west district.
Target's slowly moving
forward at 2.5km per hour.
You're late.
Sorry !
What was the observation
post at Mt. Fuji doing ?!
They didn't detect anything !
It suddenly appeared directly above us !
Pattern, orange !
No AT-field detected !
What does it mean ?
Is that a new
kind of Angel ?
Magi's withholding
their conclusion.
Geez, why's Commander Ikari
absent at a time like this ?
Everyone, do you hear me ?
Target data's sent to you.
That's all we know so far.
Engage slowly, observe its response and lure it outside the city if possible.
Unit 02 will backup
the forward, okay ?
Yes, teacher, I think Shinji
should take the forward !
Naturally.
This's a job for a brave and courageous man with the higher grade and No.1 synchro ratio.
Or Shin-chan,
maybe you aren't confident ?
I'll go !
I'll show you how it's done !
W...what did you say ?!
Hey, you guys...
You told me
I'm number one.
Well, that was...
Combat's a man's job.
How anachronistic.
Unit 02 will backup.
Unit 00 will backup, too.
Those kids've gone
on their own...
Shinji's become quite brave.
No. I'll have to
scold him when he's back.
You can be a
good babysitter.
Ayanami, Asuka,
are you in position ?
Not yet.
I can't move that fast.
Not yet ?
Well then,
I have to stop it myself.
It disappeared ?!
What ?!
Pattern blue, Angel detected
directly beneath Unit 01 !
A...shadow...
What's this ?
Something's wrong !
Shinji, get out of there !
Shinji...
Ikari...
Idiot, what're you doin' ?!
Misato, what's going on ?!
Misato...?  Asuka, Ayanami,
what happened to my backups ?!
Misato, can you hear me ?!
Eject the plug !
Send the signal !
No use !
It doesn't respond !
Misato...Misato...!
Shinji !
Asuka, Rei,
save Unit 01, hurry !
That idiot, what's the point of scoring the highest on a sham exam ?
It disappeared again.
Asuka, be careful.
Shadow...?!
No !
The city...
Asuka, Rei, withdraw.
Wai...
Wait, Unit 01 and
Ikari are still...
That's an order.
Withdraw.
Major Katsuragi is in
a difficult position.
When the umbilical cable was pulled up,
it was disconnected.
That means...
Internal power's limited...
...but if Shinji doesn't move Eva randomly and stays in life support mode...
...he can stay alive
for about sixteen hours.
Second tank squadron,
deployment complete.
Roger, wait for orders
at your current position.
Sub Laser, channel's open.
Send data.
Copy.
Transmitting on channel C.
UN Force's siege complete.
What about the shadow ?
It hasn't moved. It's been staying still ever since it reached a diameter of 600 meters.
I wonder if the ground
forces will do any good.
They want to pressure us.
Oh my, oh my, acting by himself,
ignoring the plan...
Yeah, this is all his fault.
Just because he scored
highest on yesterday's test...
...how could he say,
``I'll show you how it's done ?''
He was so elated.
W...what ?
You don't want to hear
bad things about Shinji, huh ?!
Do you pilot Eva just to
have people praise you ?
No, not by other people !
I want to praise myself !
Stop it,
both of you !
That's right.
It was a selfish act, so...
...I'll have to scold
him when he gets back.
NEON GENESIS
I never thought that going to sleep could be so tiresome.
It's completely blank.
No response on radar or sonar.
This space is too broad.
It's been twelve hours since
I switched to life support mode.
My life will last only
five or six hours...
I'm hungry.
So, that shadow's the
main part of the Angel ?
Yes, about 680 meters in diameter
and 3 nanometers thick.
It sustains that super-thin
space with an inverted AT-Field...
...and the inside is an imaginary space called ``Dirac's Ocean.''
It might be connected
to another space.
What's that sphere then ?
That should disappear when
the main body's destroyed.
That floating object
is nothing but a shadow.
The black shadow that drew
Unit 01 inside is our target...?
How can we
handle that thing ?
It's getting muddy.
The purifying function is weakening.
It smells fishy...blood...?
It's the smell of blood.
No, I can't stand this !
Why can't I unlock this ?!
Open up !
Let me outta here !
Misato, what's happening ?!
Misato, Asuka, Ayanami !
Ritsuko...Father...
Please, someone help me.
Compulsory salvage of Eva...?
That's the only method we
could come up with for now.
Dropping all existing
992 N-2 bombs into its center.
Taking timing into account and letting the two AT-field protected Evas...
...infiltrate the imaginary
area for only 1 millisecond.
Focus the explosive power
right before that moment...
...and destroy both the
Angel and the Dirac's Ocean.
But Eva's body won't...
We don't know what'll happen to Shinji !
We can't call it
a rescue operation !
Recovering the body of Unit 01 is the top priority in this operation.
Even if it's severely damaged,
it'll still be fine.
Wait a minute !
In this situation, the pilot's condition can't be taken into account.
Losing Shinji is your fault.
Don't forget that.
Why are you and Commander Ikari
so concerned about Unit 01 ?
What is Eva ?!
The information I gave
to you is everything.
You're lying !
Misato, trust me.
I'll command everything
in this operation.
We'll stage the
flights from Kanku.
Contact the JASDF's
control and mobility squadron.
The Second Impact...
Human Complement Project...Adam...
There're so many secrets
that I don't know.
Who are you ?
Ikari Shinji.
That's me.
I'm you. Everyone has
another self within them.
Two figures make
one individual.
Two ?
The one seen by others and
the one who's looking at them.
There are many
Ikari Shinjis.
The one in your mind,
the one in Katsuragi Misato's mind...
...the one in Souryu Asuka's mind,
the one in Ayanami Rei's mind...
...and the one in
Ikari Gendou's mind.
Each of them are different,
but they're all Ikari Shinji.
You're concerned about
Ikari Shinji in other's minds.
I don't want
others to hate me.
You don't want
to get hurt.
Whose fault ?
My father's fault.
It was my father
who abandoned me.
It's my fault.
You tend to think you're wrong,
that's so called self-destructive.
I'm useless.
You think you're
useless, right ?
Don't you trust
your father ?
I think I hate him,
but I'm not sure now.
Well done, Shinji.
Father called my name.
Father praised me.
So, you want to live
with that happiness.
If I trust his words,
I can live.
By deceiving yourself...?
Everyone's the same.
Everyone lives by doing that.
If you don't believe you're doing alright, you can't live.
There're too many hardships
for me to live in my world.
For example,
you can't swim ?
Humans aren't
born to float.
It's self deception.
Whatever you want
to call it !
You've closed your eyes and shut your ears to unpleasant matters.
In that incident,
his sister was...
It doesn't matter
what others think !
Go home !
No, I don't
want to hear it !
See, you're running
away again.
You can't live by spinning
only a thread of happiness.
Particularly, I can't.
I found something interesting.
To find something interesting
and stick to it...
...what's wrong with that ?!
The entry plug's backup power has
reached its theoretical limit.
The plug suit's life support system has almost reached the danger zone.
Let's move up our
schedule twelve minutes.
While there's a possibility
that Shinji's still alive...
Father, am I an
unwanted child ?
Father !
You ran away yourself.
That's right, he might be
the one who killed his wife !
He killed his wife !
No !
My mother was smiling.
You did something
you can be proud of.
Shinji, don't run away.
Good luck.
I don't want to be...
...alone...
I don't want...
The temperature control and
air circulation have stopped.
It's cold.
No, the suit's
reaching its limit.
Is it over ?
I'm tired of...
...everything.
Mother...?!
Are you satisfied ?
I see, that's good.
The two Eva units
are in position.
Get ready to generate
the AT-field.
Roger.
Sixty seconds to bomb drop.
What's happening ?!
Status ?
Not sure !
All gauges are
off the scale !
We haven't done anything !
Could that be Shinji ?
Impossible !
Unit 01's power is zero !
Am I piloting
something like ``that''...?!
What...what did
we copy it from ?
I know it's not just
a copy of the first Angel...
...but what will NERV do with Eva when it defeats all the Angels ?
Shinji...Shinji...Shinji...
Shinji...
Are you alright, Shinji ?
I just wanted
to see...again.
Aren't you supposed
to scold him ?
I never thought that the Eva
was so frightening, until today.
I wonder if Eva's
really on our side.
It might hate us.
Major Katsuragi might have
become aware of something.
I see.
It's alright for now.
If Rei and Shinji become aware of
Eva's secret, they won't forgive us.
Stay in bed today.
We'll take care of the rest.
I'm alright.
Really ?
That's good.
I can't get rid of
the smell of blood.
TO BE CONTINUED
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
Rei/Mother: Megumi Hayashibara~
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Preview
Eva Unit 04 under development
in Nevada, explodes...
...during its activation experiment
along with NERV 2nd Command.
The old men of Seele modify
their scenario themselves.
And the Fourth Child
was selected.
Next time:
``The Fourth Child.''