Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
NEON GENESIS
Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
You've denied us the interrogation of Unit 01's pilot...
...the only person concerned in the incident, Major Katsuragi.
Yes, sir.
His emotions are unstable.
I don't think it's a good idea for him to stand before you at this moment.
Then, we'll question you
in his place, Major Katsuragi.
During the incident, is it true that the Angel tried to make contact with a human ?
The incident report doesn't suggest that.
Presumably, it was an isolated incident.
So long as he
remembers correctly.
No external interference with
his memory was detected.
Eva's AC recorder wasn't operating.
There's no way to confirm that.
Was the Angel interested in
the human spirit or mind ?
I'm not able to
answer that question.
Do Angels have the concept of mind ?
Do they understand human thoughts ?
These are unknowns.
This incident revealed the Angels' new tactic of trying to possess the Eva.
What about the possiblity of that tactic being linked to the predicted 13th Angel ?
Considering the patterns so far, systematic coupling among the Angels is negative.
That's right. So far, it's obvious that their actions have been independent.
What does that mean ?
You're not permitted
to ask questions.
Understood.
That's it.
Dismissed.
Yes, sir.
What do you think, Ikari ?
Angels are becoming more
and more intelligent.
The time left is...
...``very short.''
Is that what you mean ?
Episode 17
The Fourth Child
The patient in room 12 ?
You mean the medical treatment given during Incident E ?~~That was a while ago.
That was a
very serious injury.
She's still
an elementary student.
Has that boy
come today ?
Yeah. He always
visits twice a week.
He's a very good brother,
thinking about his sister so much.
That's right !
Boys like that are rare nowadays.
SUZUHARA
Rei, are you
alright today ?
Yes. Tomorrow, I will be with Dr. Akagi.
The day after tomorrow, school.
How is school ?
I have no problems.
I see. Very well, then.
Stand up.
Bow. Sit.
Oh, are Ayanami and
Aida absent again ?
Kensuke, how come ?
New Yokosuka. Following
battleships today as usual.
I hear that something called
``Myoukou'' is in port.
Suzuhara !
Y...ye...yes ?!
Take the printouts
to Ayanami later.
Yes, sir !
Anyhow, the 1st Branch's
status is good !
No need ! Magi will confirm
the reconnaissance plane's data !
Vanished ?!
The 2nd Branch really vanished ?
Yes. It's confirmed.
It vanished.
This is bad.
The Administration and Inspection
Departments are in an uproar.
The General Affairs
Department is in a panic.
And the cause...?
Still under investigation.
The only clue is
this satellite image.
Nothing else remains.
Juu byou...
...hachi...
...nana...
...roku...
...go...
...yon...
...san...
...ni...
...ichi...
TMZEB
How horrible !
Evangelion Unit 04, along with all installations within a 89km radius, have vanished.
Including thousands of people.
From the time schedule...
...the accident apparently occured during the installation of the experimental ``S2'' engine.
Data is insufficient, but a possible cause might've been an error in the initial design.
The number of possible
combinations is 32,768.
There's a possibilty
of sabotage.
But it wasn't an explosion,
it was a disappearance.
Probably swallowed by Dirac's Ocean,
just like Unit 01.
Then, the
``S2'' engine also...
Vanished...
Along with our dream.
It's because they forced us to use something we don't understand.
Eva's also such a thing.
So, how is Unit 03 ?
We're about to receive it. The U.S. administration didn't lose the 1st Branch.
They insisted on the right
to build Units 03 and 04.
But now they force us to accept it.
They're pushing their luck.
After that tragedy,
anyone could lose courage.
Will we do the activation test
using Rei's dummy plug ?
I'll decide.
This is a
prototype dummy plug.
Rei's personality was transferred, but the human mind and spirit can't be digitized.
This is nothing but
a fake, an imitation.
It mimics the pilot's thinking.
It's just a machine.
It transmits a
signal pattern to Eva.
Eva believes that a pilot is present and synchronizes with it.
That's what we need.
Install the data in Units 01 and 02.
This still has
some problems.
It doesn't matter.
As long as Eva moves.
Understood.
The transportation of the Unit is being left entirely to UN.
It will arrive this weekend.
Then you'll have work to do.
Yes, sir. The adjustment and activation test will be done at Matsushiro.
The test pilot...?
The dummy plug is still dangerous.
One of the present candidates will be...
...appointed as the Fourth.
Yes, sir. There's one child whose
core will be ready immediately.
I leave it to you.
Yes, sir.
Rei, it's over.
Okay.
Let's go eat.
Stand up. Bow.
Alright, it's time to eat !
It's the greatest pleasure in school life.
You didn't make
our lunches ?!
La...last night,
I was too busy doing homework...
And because of that, you're saying I have to go without lunch ?!
My, my. A quarrel
between husband and wife ?
NO WAY !
What're you
so serious about ?
For Unit 03's activation test at Matsushiro,
we'll use the Fourth as the pilot.
The Fourth ?
The Fourth Child was found ?
Yesterday.
I haven't received a report
from the Marduk Institute yet.
The official documents
will arrive tomorrow.
Dr. Akagi, are you keeping
secrets from me again ?
Of course not.
Well, alright.
And who is it ?
Isn't there anyone else ?!
We had no choice. The candidates were collected in one place for their protection.
I don't know about this.
Asuka's okay.
She's proud to pilot the Eva.
Rei is Rei.
It's not good if it
concerns Eva and other matters.
Shinji knows about
these matters best.
I don't want him to
experience any more pain.
But we need children like
them if we are to survive.
You're telling me,
``Don't avoid complications.''
Bye !
Suzuhara, you're on duty today.
Do your duty.
What're ya talkin' about ?
The printouts.
The teacher said
to deliver these.
Oh, come on, Class Rep.
There must be someone else.
Ayanami's absent today.
Ayanami and me ?
Then I have no choice.
But I can't go to a
woman's apartment alone.
Then I'll go with you...
Shinji !~~You come
with me, okay ?!
Ayanami, I'm coming in.
It ain't good to enter
a woman's apartment uninvited.
We don't have a choice.
She won't notice if we put them here.
Excuse me.
Oh, this's a woman's room ?
Not very charming.
Hey, don't touch anything,
she'll get angry.
I'm only cleaning up.
I won't help you.
It's not a man's job.
Alright then.
But Misato hates guys like that.
I...I don't mind.
`Cause it's my policy.
Man, quite a change.
What ?
You, Shinji.
When I first met you,
I thought you were a jerk.
You didn't seem like a guy who'd do things for the sake of others.
Anyhow, it's just
that you're quiet.
Sorry to disturb you.
What ?
Those are your printouts.
Sorry. I cleaned up on my own.
I didn't pick up anything but trash.
Th...thank you.
Well, I guess it's true that
all Eva pilots are strange.
``Thank you.''
The word for gratitude.
The first time
I've used it.
I've never said
it to ``that'' person.
NEON GENESIS
This city is a paradise
that humans built.
Driven out of paradise...
...fleeing to that world on earth where humans live near death.
Made by those
weakest of beings...
...made with wisdom acquired because of that weakness. A paradise of our own.
To protect us from the fear of death, to satisfy ourselves with joy, was made a paradise...
This city is
such a place.
Equipped with weapons
to protect ourselves.
A city for those cowardly people
fleeing a world full of enemies.
Cowardly people live longer.
That's one good thing.
Tokyo-3, NERV's camouflaged
intercept fortress city.
The long-delayed 7th construction
phase will be completed.
How are you going to report Unit 04's
accident to the committee ?
Tell the truth.
The cause is unknown.
But there was great
damage this time.
I don't care about Unit 04
or the 2nd Branch.
We lost the ``S2'' engine sample,
and the remaining data is in Germany.
Unit 01 and this
installation are enough.
But the committee
is panicking.
Naturally. It was
an unscheduled incident.
Seele must be busy
revising the schedule.
Incidents missing from the
Dead Sea Scrolls may happen.
It will teach those
old men a lesson.
The transformation of the 3rd Area and the prototype weapon test will...
Although the intercept system will finally be completed, no celebration is scheduled.
NERV is very strict.
That's the way
Commander Ikari is.
How about you ?
Are you sure about this, Kaji ?
I'll tell Katsuragi and Akagi.
Before you say anything,
I'll cover your mouth.
How's business ?
Oh, normal.
Well, I have work to do.
Excuse me.
Although I don't say anything
about your private life...
Please don't seduce young
girls during this emergency.
It isn't your job to enforce that.
And it's okay if it's you, Katsuragi.
That depends on the answer
you're about to give.
You must know the secrets of
the Marduk Institute and ADAM.
Huh ?
Don't play dumb
with me.
It's not like you to
ask someone for help.
I don't care what
people say about me.
I'm not reserved
at the moment.
Coincidentally,
the Fourth Child was found.
What's the reason
for hiding that ?
I'll tell you one thing.
The Marduk Institute
does not exist.
There's nothing but NERV
pulling the strings.
Nothing but NERV ?
Commander Ikari ?
Code 7-0-7.
Investigate it.
7-0-7 ?
Shinji's school ?
Misato.
What ?
Ritsuko's expecting you at the meeting for tomorrow's business trip.
Alright, thanks.
We'll talk later.
Okay, okay.
How about having a
cup of tea with me ?
I'm a guy.
I thought you'd
be more serious.
You'd say such things
to someone reliable, Ikari Shinji ?
Oh...s...sorry.
No, I'm sorry too. I didn't mean to say anything unpleasant.
Oh yeah. I'll show you
something good.
Watermelon ?
Don't you think it's cute ?
This is my hobby.
Don't tell anyone.
Making or growing
something is good !
We see and learn many
things through that.
Also enjoyable.
Also painful.
Do you dislike pain ?
I don't like it.
Did you find
something enjoyable ?
That's good. Someone who
knows pain is kinder to others.
That's the opposite of weakness.
Yes, hello.
It's from Katsuragi.
A synchro-test will be held soon.
It's true. Shinji's synchro
ratio is getting worse.
What does it mean ?
I can't say. But I suppose something happened during the last incident, something mental.
It's going to be even more difficult to tell him about Unit 03's pilot.
The person himself will be
officially notified tomorrow.
Stand up. Attention. Bow.
Alright, it's
time ta eat !
Suzuhara Touji of
second year, A Class.
Suzuhara Touji, come to the
Director's office immediately.
What the...?
Did you do something ?
Well, nothing I remember.
Suzuhara Touji, entering.
You're Suzuhara Touji, right ?
How was your trip
to New Yokosuka yesterday ?
Absolutely great !~~By the way, I've obtained some disturbing information.
Eva Unit 03 ?
Right. The one under construction in the U.S.~~I guess it's completed.
I have no idea.
I know you have to keep it secret, but please tell me.
I haven't heard anything.
Have you heard the rumor that the activation test...
...will be held at 2nd Experiment Installation in Matsushiro ?
I don't know.
Has the pilot
been chosen ?
I don't know.
Misato could let
me pilot it.
Hey, Shinji, please ask her.
I really want to pilot Eva.
Really, I don't know.
Then how about the rumor
about losing Unit 04 ?
What ?
You really don't know ?
The 2nd Branch was destroyed.
My dad's section was going crazy.
Really ?
I guess.
Misato hasn't
told me anything.
The pilot at the end of the
system has nothing to do with it.
If she didn't tell you,
I guess you don't need to know.
Sorry about asking
strange questions.
Anyway, Touji's pretty late.
We human beings survived the hell of the Second Impact, and rose up afterwards.
Currently, the birthrate
decreases every year.
Sorry for being late.
I heard.
Have a seat.
Well, those younger generations
are torchbearers of the future...
Hey, let's go home.
Where's Touji ?
He'll be late
because he's on duty.
It's time to go home.
We strongly suggest...
Suzuhara.
You're on duty. You have to align desks and write the daily record.
I haven't had lunch yet.
When I'm finished, I will.
Your lunch is always
from the school store.
Nobody cooks for me.
Suzuhara...
I have two sisters,
Kodama and Nozomi.
I always cook
lunch for them.
That's a lot of
work for you.
Well, I'm quite good at cooking,
though you might not imagine it.
But I always have leftover
ingredients for the lunches.
What a waste.
I'll help you all I can with
the disposal of leftovers.
Oh, please.
Kaji.
Oh, Asuka. Sorry, I'm very busy.
Can you wait ?
But you have
time to see Misato.
Hey !
Not now !
This is our synchro-data.
Four ?
What ?!
What does this mean ?!
Why's THIS guy
the Fourth Child ?!
No, I don't understand !
What's going on ?!
NERV, 1st Branch, USA
TO BE CONTINUED
Translation
Onizuka Kentaro
Editing
Todd Perkins
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
Version 1.0
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Eva Unit 03 is delivered to Matsushiro from America.
People gloried in the peaceful day, unaware of the coming tragedy.
The quiet days that collusion has camouflaged are gone.
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~~
Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu~
~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Kirl: Mugito~~~~~~~
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Next Episode:
``The Judgement of Life.''