Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
SHIN SEIKI
''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
Hey, where's Asuka ?
She's already gone.
She's trying to avoid me.
Why ?
Shin-chan, it seems women's hearts are still too hard for you to understand.
Umm...
By the way...
Go ahead.
Is the rumor about
Unit 04 being lost true ?
I heard it was
destroyed in an accident.
Yes, it's true. Unit 04's gone,
along with NERV 2nd Branch.
It was during the
``S2'' engine test.
We're alright here, though.
All three units are working fine.
The pilots and staff
are both excellent, too.
But I heard Unit 03
is coming from the U.S...
The activation test will take
place at Matsushiro, right ?
Yeah. I'll be gone about 4 days. But don't worry, Kaji will take care of you guys.
But what about the test ?
Since Ritsuko will be there,
there won't be any problems.
But what about the pilot ?
Well, about the pilot...
Coming !
Good morning, ma'am !
I came here today to make
a request of Major Katsuragi.
Please, make me the pilot
of Evangelion Unit 03.
THE~~~~~~~~~~~~~
JUDGEMENT
~~~~~~~~OF LIFE
Shinji doesn't know yet ?
I just can't find the
right time to tell him.
I'm afraid to, since I can't figure out what he's thinking.
Come on, you're the one who wanted to be his guardian.
Yeah, I know...
So, when will the
pilot be called ?
Tomorrow, since there are
preparations to be made.
He may talk
about it himself.
Not likely. He wasn't happy
enough to brag about it.
His only condition was the transfer of his little sister to HQ's medical unit.
Misato's really mean.
I'm the most willing, so why don't they use me as backup ?
Right, Touji ?
Huh ?
Oh, right.
What's wrong ?~~You left home before me, but you're late.
What, no marital
quarrel today ?
I just didn't want to see your faces, you Three Stooges !
Now for lunch.
Hey, where's Touji ?
I haven't seen
him anywhere.
He left without eating lunch ?
That's not possible.
He's been acting
weird lately.
Suzuhara...
Huh ?
Oh, it's you, Ayanami.
If you're looking for Shinji,
he ain't here.
You know about me ?
Souryu seems to know too.
Yes.
Shinji's the only
one who doesn't know.
It's really unusual for
you to worry about others.
Really ?
I don't understand.
You're worried about Shinji.
Really...?
Maybe that's true.
Yep.
Hikari !
Let's eat !
Two hours late already,
and he's here at last.
He's the first guy to
make me wait this long.
When you were dating you just left without waiting, right ?
Therefore, it was the incident
known as the Second Impact.
I was living in Nebukawa
at the time, but now...
...it's underwater because Antarctica's icecap melted and the waters rose.
Sorry, transferee. But I had to hit you. I couldn't be satisfied unless I hit you.
I'm sorry, Asuka.
You usually walk home with Ikari.
Don't worry, I'm only
with Shinji as a duty...
...and I'm not in a mood
to see his face right now.
It's about Suzuhara, right ?
Yes. Can you tell ?
It's so easy to see.
Only the Three Stooges can't see.
But, Ikari seems so naive.
He's the dullest. An idiot. He doesn't know how to get along with others.
I see.
Ayanami might be
the girl Suzuhara likes.
Suzuhara likes the
teacher's pet ?!
They were getting
along well during lunch.
Don't worry, Hikari.
That girl knows how to get along with people 1/10000th as well as Shinji.
Really ?
Really !
May I ask
a question ?
What ?
Why do you like that
hotheaded idiot ?
He's kind.
Oh, then making up with
you was a mistake !
Don't tell me that now...
By the way...
Kaji sure takes a
long time to bathe.
Who'll pilot Unit 03 ?
What ?
You haven't heard yet ?
Who is it ?
I don't know.
Great bath.
Bickering again ?
I can't believe it.
Are you two like this
whenever Katsuragi's gone ?
No !~~I want to smile prettily since you're staying with me tonight.
But not today.
I can't smile !
I understand.
Let's get some sleep.
Hitting the hay is the best
solution in situations like this.
Are you asleep yet, Kaji ?
No, not yet.
What kind of person
is my father ?
Well, I'm surprised
by that question.
I thought you were going
to ask about Katsuragi.
It seems like you're
always with him.
The Deputy Commander is the one who's with him all the time.
Have you been asking around
about your father ?
I wasn't with him
for a long time...
So, you don't know.
But I've started to understand many things about my father recently.
About his job,
about my mother. So...
You're wrong. You just
think you understand.
Well, that's why people try to know each other. You never learn everything about them.
Well, that's why life's
so interesting.
Does that fit your
relationship with Misato, too ?
For us, women exist
on the opposite shore.
There's a river wider and deeper than the ocean between men and women.
I can't understand grownups.
Unit 03 activation test:
T minus 30 minutes.
2nd Experiment
Installation
Underground temporal cage
(No human)
Above ground facility
Primary power,
standing by.
Apotheosis No.2,
all clear.
Refrigeration systems in all
sections functioning at standard levels.
Pressure lock on left
arm secured in place.
Eva Unit 03
activation test
control center.
Central command
vehicle (interior)
Roger. Team B, start
the operation.
Data link to
Evangelion Unit 03 established.
It's possible to use
this in combat now.
Oh, how nice.
You don't sound
very enthusiastic.
When this unit is delivered
it will be under your direct command.
Exclusive possession of four Evas...
If we wanted to, we could end the world.
Did you tell Shinji ?
After the test.
Fourth Child has arrived. Squad 2, begin entry preparations immediately.
He hasn't
come yet, Asuka.
He may not
come today.
I thought he
would eat today.
Do you want it ?
Unit 03 should be
in Japan now, right ?
Yes. I think
it arrived yesterday.
I'm so jealous.
Who's gonna ride it ?
Touji, maybe ?
He's absent today.
No way.
Entry plug secured.
Begin phase one connection.
Transmitting pulses.
Graph display within norms.
List clear through 1-3-5-0.
Phase one contact, all clear.
Roger. Transfer the
operation to phase two.
Full nerve link established.
List clear through 2-5-5-0.
Harmonics all reading standard.
Approaching absolute threshold.
Abort the test.
Cut the circuits.
No good !~~There's a huge power surge coming from inside the unit !
Can it be...
...an Angel ?
NEON GENESIS
An explosion at Matsushiro.
Status unknown.
Send a rescue team and 3rd Squad. Take care of everything before the JSDF arrives.
Roger.
Unidentified object
moving at the site.
Pattern orange.
Can't be identified as an Angel.
First class combat alert.
First class combat alert !
Prepare for ground combat !
All Evas to go and take position at the counterattack point.
Air transportation is
planned to start in 20.
An accident at Matsushiro ?
Oh, no...What about
Misato and the others ?
There's no contact yet.
Oh, no.
What should I do ?
What're you whining about ?!
We can't do anything but worry now !
But we have to go against
the Angel on our own...
Commander Ikari is
taking direct command.
My father is...?
We have the visual from Nobeyama.
Visual on the main screen.
Just as we thought.
Transmit the terminal signal. Execute forced ejection of the entry plug.
Impossible. It won't recognize either the terminal signal or the ejection code.
What about the pilot ?
We have his respiration
and pulse, however...
From this moment, Evangelion Unit 03 is expendable...
...and the target is identified
as the 13th angel.
B...but, sir.
Draw the line at Nobeyama as planned,
and destroy the target.
Target approaching.
All units, stand by
for ground battle.
No way. An Angel ?
You mean that's an Angel ?
Yes.
That's the target.
The target ?
That's...an Eva.
I can't believe it.
Taken over by an Angel ?
Is it piloted by a kid,
just like ours ?
Don't you know yet ?
Unit 03's pilot is...
Asuka ?
Asuka !
Eva Unit 02, down !
Pilot has ejected.
Salvage crew on the way.
Target is moving
toward Unit 00.
Rei, avoid close combat and stop the target. I'll send Unit 01 soon.
Roger.
``He's'' inside.
The Angel's invading
Unit 00's left arm.
The nerve joint
is being invaded.
Sever the
left arm, hurry.
But that'll cut
the nerve connection.
Sever it now.
Yes, sir.
Moderate damage to Unit 00.
Pilot has been injured.
No...
The target is approaching. Contact within 20. Take care of it.
You're saying
it's the target...
But isn't there
someone in there ?
A kid my age.
An entry plug.
There is someone inside.
Trouble with life support.
The pilot's in danger.
This isn't good.
Cut synchronization to 60% !
Wait.
But if you maintain this status,
the pilot will die.
Shinji, why don't
you fight ?
But there's a
person inside, Father.
It doesn't matter.
It's an Angel. Our Enemy.
But I can't do that. I have to save the pilot. I can't kill another person.
You'll die.
I don't care. It's better
than killing someone.
Very well, cut the synchronization of the pilot and Unit 01 completely.
Cut it off, sir ?
Yes. Switch the circuit
to the dummy plug.
But sir, the dummy system still has many problems, and without Dr. Akagi's direction...
It'll work better
than the pilot. Do it.
Yes, sir.
What the...?
What'd you do, Father ?!
Signal reception comfirmed.
Control system switched.
All nerves now connected
to the dummy system.
32.8% of the emotional factor
is unclear. Unable to monitor.
It doesn't matter.
Release the system. Commence attack.
Is this the power
of the dummy plug ?
All systems normal.
More increase in gain.
Stop !
Father, stop !
Please stop doing this !
Damn !
Stop !
Stop !~~~
STOP !
E...Eva Unit 03...
...I mean,
target completely silenced.
This looks good.
Kodama, Nozomi and me.
Lunch for four.
Will he eat tomorrow  ?
Over here ! A survivor !
BQR, get the medics, hurry !
Yes, that recorder's graphs...
Get rid of it.
I'm alive...
Kaji...?
You were lucky, Katsuragi.
How's Ritsuko ?
Don't worry.
Her condition's
better than yours.
I see.
What about Eva Unit 03 ?
It was handled as
an Angel by Unit 01.
I...I haven't told
Shinji anything yet.
Shinji...
Misato, you're alright.
I...I'm sorry. I had to tell you something important, but...
Misato, I've...I've...
My father...
I begged him not to...
Shinji, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Report from the
entry plug salvage crew.
Survival of the
pilot confirmed.
Still alive.
Roger. Cut the deformed
part with a laser.
Send altered LCL
sample to the
lab as a priority.
Cut trapped biological parts.
Prepare for cauterization.
Unit 03's pilot is...
The Fourth Child is...
Touji ?
Shinji ?
Shinji ?!
TO BE CONTINUED
Translation
Mie Kominami
Editing
Todd Perkins
Dave
Brain
Barbara
The Doctor
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Preview
On his own, Shinji decides to quit his position as a pilot.
Once again, the separation begins.
As an Angel destroys Unit 02 and Unit 00, Shinji makes his decision.
Next episode: "A Man's Fight"