Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
NEON GENESIS
Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
Unit 01's synchronization
circuit has been cut.
What about the
ejection signal ?
It's locked from inside the plug.
It won't accept it.
Shinji, you would've been
killed if he hadn't done that.
It doesn't matter.
But it's the truth.
Don't make me
any more angry.
There's 185 seconds left in Unit 01.
I can still destroy half of headquarters.
In his current condition,
he might really do it.
Shinji, listen to me !
Everyone might have been killed if Commander Ikari didn't make his decision.
I said it
doesn't matter !
Father...
...he tried to kill Touji...
...with my hands.
Episode 19
Man's Battle
Father, you're there,
aren't you ?!
Say something !
Answer me !
Increase LCL compression
density to maximum setting.
We don't have time
for an irritated child.
There's another
direct connection...
Damn it...
...damn it...
D...damn it ...
Dissolution of the
right breast, complete.
Cleaning of body fluid will
begin from 3-0 as planned.
Part No.6 will be heated.
Are you alright ?
It's alright as long
as I can do my job.
I can't take a break during
this emergency situation.
What about Shinji ?
He was forcefully removed after they used the laser cutter to open the emergency hatch.
This is tough.
This time...
...he might not make it.
That idiot won't
be able to recover.
What about Ikari ?
He's not injured, so he'll
wake up sooner or later.
He's probably dreaming now.
Dream...?
Yes.
Haven't you had a dream ?
Shinji...?
Why's Shinji sleeping beside me ?
Where am I ?
The hospital where my sister is...?
Oh, Shinji and Ayanami...
Why did you do that, Ikari ?
I couldn't forgive my father...
...he betrayed me.
I was happy to talk to
him after so much trouble.
He doesn't understand
how I feel.
Did you try to
understand him ?
I tried.
Why don't you try
to understand him ?
I tried to understand !
You're running away
from difficulties.
What's wrong...?
What's wrong with running
away from difficulties ?!
Why're they arguing ?
Your visit is an exception,
so you only have five minutes.
Sure.
Thank you very much.
Oh, Class Rep...
Suzuhara, are you alright ?
Yeah.
I guess I'm alive.
I thought Shinji was there,
but I guess it was a dream.
He left the hospital yesterday.
You've been sleeping for three days.
I see.
For three days...
Why're you...
I came here as class
representative, nothing else.
Yeah, I know.
No, you don't.
I'm sorry...that your lunch.
It's okay. I feel sorry that
you can't eat lunch here.
Class Rep...
What ?
Can I ask
you a favor ?
Yes.
Tell my sister
that I'm alright.
Okay.
Come on, Ikari Shinji.
The Commander wants to see you.
Disobedience, selfish possession of Eva and threats. These are all crimes.
Do you have
anything to say ?
Yes. I don't want to pilot Eva,
and I don't want to stay here either.
Then, leave.
Sure, I'll go back
to the teacher's place.
Are you going
to run away again ?
You disappoint me.
We won't meet again.
Sure, that's what I want.
It's me. Delete everything
about the Third Child.
Use the dummy plug for Unit 01
by converting to Rei's basics.
Shinji, is it true
that you're leaving ?
It's true, isn't it ?
But why ?
Why're you running away ?
I was envious because you were
different from me and the others.
Damn, even Touji
can pilot Eva, but I...
This phone's being monitored.
The call was cut off to maintain security.
Thank you for
your cooperation.
Asuka must've been so
disgusted that she wouldn't come.
Right. She didn't even
send her regards.
Just like her,
I'm satisfied.
If you keep trying to act like
that you'll have a hard time.
That's your style of living.
I can't do that.
I think you know, but your actions will be restricted from now on, alright ?
I know.
Umm...
What ?
Tell me one thing.
Why did the Fourth Child
have to be Touji ?
All of your classmates
were the fourth candidate.
I came to know that very recently.
Everything was already prepared.
Everyone...everyone in the class...?
We can't make amends for the incident with Suzuhara no matter how much we apologize.
But, Shinji, honestly speaking, I overlaid my dreams, hopes and purposes on yours.
I know I was imposing
on you with that.
But we...the people of NERV,
had to entrust our future to you.
Keep that
in mind, okay ?
It's so selfish, isn't it ?
I know that.
I'll keep your pass code
to HQ and your room.
Don't waste your time.
You can get rid of them.
I'll never pilot Eva.
He's speaking so spontaneously.
It's never happened before.
A state of emergency has
been issued for the Tokai area.
Area residents, please go to
designated shelters immediately.
I repeat...
An Angel.
NEON GENESIS
All personnel, first class battle stations.
Prepare for surface to air combat.
What about the target ?
Still advancing. It's broken through the defensive line at Komagatake.
First through eighteenth
layers are damaged.
Eighteen special armor
plates were so easily...
We won't be able to send
Eva to the surface in time !
Position Unit 02 inside
the Geo-Front to protect HQ !
Have Asuka attack the target as soon as it enters the Geo-Front.
What about Unit 00 ?
It's stationed at the
AT-Field neutralizing zone.
The left arm
hasn't been restored.
Incapable of combat...?
Send Rei in Unit 01.
Prepare the dummy
plug for back-up.
Yes, sir.
Start entry.
LCL, charged.
Start connecting the
A10 nerve circuit.
It won't work any more.
The pulse is
flowing in reverse.
Unit 01's rejecting
the nerve connection.
No, it shouldn't be...
Ikari...
Yeah. It's going
to reject me.
Stop activation.
Send Rei in Unit 00.
Reactivate Unit 01
with the dummy plug.
But Unit 00...
It's alright. I'll go.
Even if I die,
substitutes are available.
I've decided not
to pilot again.
Hey, what're you doing ?
Go to the shelter now.
It's no good !~~One more hit will break through all armor plating !
I'm counting on you, Asuka.
Here you come.
I can handle this easily
without Shinji around.
Damn you.
Next.
The AT-Field was supposed
to be neutralized...
Why can't I destroy it ?!
I can't lose again !
No way !
Damn you !
Asuka ! Cut all
nerve connections, quickly !
Evacuation drill...?
Are you stupid ?
It's got nothing
to do with us pilots.
It's landed on
the sixth shelter.
Abandon the sixth shelter. Those who survived, get to the third shelter.
Unit 02, severely damaged !
Disabled !
What about Asuka ?
She's alright.
She's alive.
Damn.
The Angel has
started to move.
What about Unit 01 ?
Dummy plug's been inserted.
Pulse induced.
Start connecting.
Okay.
What ?
The pulse faded out !
It rejected the dummy plug !
It's no use, we're unable
to activate Unit 01 !
The dummy...and Rei...
It's not accepting.
Fuyutsuki...
...take charge for a moment.
Carry the injured
to the sixth block !
Have the survivors get
to the third shelter !
This way !
Hurry !
Hurry up !~~Move it !
What're you doing ?!
Do you want to die ?!
Asuka...
Oh, it's you, Shinji.
Kaji...
What're you doing here ?
That's my line.
What are you doing, Shinji ?
I...I won't pilot Eva.
I've made up my mind.
I see.
My part time job was brought to light,
so I don't have anything to do during battle.
I've been watering ever since.
At a time like this ?
Because of a
time like this...
Katsuragi's breasts may be comfortable,
but I want to be here when I die.
Die...
Yes, if the Angel makes contact with Adam being kept underneath...
...everybody'll be killed
because of the Third Impact.
Only Evangelion, which has power equal to the Angels, can prevent it.
Ayanami...without even
a rifle...?!
Is she going
to self-destruct...?
Rei !
The AT-Field, maximum.
What about Unit 00 ?
Rei !
Why did she...?
Shinji, all I can do is spray water. But you have something you, and only you, can do.
No one will force you,
so decide for yourself...
...what you should do now...
...so that you
won't regret it.
Direct hit on
the third basement !
Last armor melted !
Oh, no !~~The main shaft
was fully exposed !
Isn't Unit 01 active yet ?!
It refused the dummy plug !
It's no good,
there's no response !
Continue.
Repeat from 108.
Let me pilot it !
Let me...let me...
Let me pilot Unit 01 !
Father...
Why are you still here ?
I'm...I'm the pilot
of Evangelion Unit 01...
...Ikari Shinji !
The target's entered the main shaft,
and it's descending !
Its destination...?
It's heading for
Central Dogma !
It's coming here !
All personnel, evacuate immediately !
All personnel, evacuate !
I repeat. All personnel...
Eva Unit 01...!
Shinji...?!
Misato !
Launch No.5, now !
Energy's out.
Unit 01's reached its activation limit !
Back-up's not working either !
Shinji...
Shinji !
Move, move, move, move...
please, move !
If you don't move now,
everything'll be over !
That's...
Move, move, move !
Move, move, move,
move, move, move !
Move, move,
move, damn it !
If you don't move now...
If I can't do it now, everyone'll die !
I can't stand it !
So, please move !
E...Eva reactivated.
Incredible...
It can't be.
I can't believe this...
Unit 01's synchro ratio
is exceeding 400 percent.
She's awakened after all.
It's eating the Angel...
Is Eva Unit 01 trying to take
the S2 organ into itself...?
The binders...
Binders...?
Yes. That's not armor. Those are the binders to suppress Eva's innate power.
And it's shedding the binders itself.
No one can stop Eva any more.
The awakening and
liberation of Unit 01...
...SEELE won't remain silent.
Is this a part of your scenario,
Commander Ikari ?
It's begun.
Yeah.
Now, everything begins.
TO BE CONTINUED
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
Version 1.1
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Mankind has been saved by the Eva's awakening,
but its pilot has been physically fused with the Eva.
Shinji's been fused with another existence. What will he see?
What was it that the crying Misato saw?
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~~
Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu~
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Next time:
``Shape of Heart, Shape of Human''