Translated by Wada Mitsuhito (Wada-kun)
Timed by: Todd Perkins
Edited by: Todd Perkins, Hiroaki Fukuda, Dave
SHIN SEIKI
''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
It's eating the Angel.
And it's shedding the binders itself.
No one can stop Eva any more.
The awakening and
liberation of Unit 01...
...SEELE won't remain silent.
The Eva series is not supposed to be equipped with the S2 organ.
I didn't expect it to use such
a manner to take that in.
That incident was very
different from our scenario.
It won't be
easy to amend.
Was it our mistake to have
Ikari Gendou command NERV ?
But only he can
complete our plan.
Ikari, what are
you thinking ?
It's begun.
Yeah.
Now, everything begins.
EPISODE 20
\C7Shape of Heart
( kokoro no katachi )
Shape of Human
( hito no katachi )
The damage to Eva is
exceeding ``Heiflick'' limits.
It'll take time
to restore everything.
Fortunately, it's possible to
transplant the Magi system.
We'll start tomorrow.
But this place is useless.
It's only a matter of time
before this place is abandoned.
Right. We have to use the secondary command post for now.
Without Magi...?
Yes. Wipe the dust off and we'll be back to work this afternoon.
The chairs are too close together, and the sensors are tough to operate.
It's not so
comfortable, is it ?
The layout is similar to the
first command post, though...
I just feel awkward.
At least we
can ``use'' it.
We're not sure if
we can use Unit 01.
Is it sufficient to
bind it in the cage ?
There are no signs of heat, electronic, magnetic or chemical reactions.
The S2 organ has
completely stopped.
Nevertheless, Unit 01 has
moved three times before.
We shouldn't make assumptions
based on appearances.
We don't know what'll happen if we touch it carelessly.
It's just like you, Katsuragi.
Sorry.
Eva Unit 01 is not
the only problem.
Exactly. Severe damage to Units 00 and 02,
massive damage to headquarters...
...exposure of Central Dogma.
Our loss is very serious.
We don't know how much
time and money we've lost.
It was because we didn't put
a bell around Ikari's neck.
The bell was there,
but it didn't ring.
A silent bell is useless.
Have the bell take action this time.
It was an unexpected
development, wasn't it ?
The committee...What's the excuse you'll use with SEELE ?
Unit 01 wasn't under our control.
It was an unfortunate accident.
So, I'll restrain Unit 01 until the committee answers me.
That's an appropriate reaction.
But your son's still inside.
It didn't work after all. It doesn't accept the ejection signal to the entry plug.
What about the back-up
and simulated signals ?
They've been rejected. I can't establish a direct connection.
The visual line to the plug has been connected. I'm displaying it on the main monitor.
What's going on ?
That's the true meaning of the
400 percent of the synchro ratio.
No. Then what
happened to Shinji ?
He was assimilated
into Eva Unit 01.
What do you mean ?
What is Eva ?
All I can say is that it's a human shaped object created by humans.
Created by humans...? You just copied the one you found in Antarctica, didn't you ?
How could that
be an original ?
It's not an ordinary copy,
because it has a human will.
Do you mean that this
was someone's decision ?
Or maybe Eva's.
Do something !
You built it, didn't you ?!
Take your responsibility to the end !
The government and the Ministry of the Interior officially denied it.
Next news...It's been a month since the terrorist attack by a sect in Tokyo-2.
To prevent another
terrorist attack...
I'm still alive.
I understand that
she's alright !
Don't call me about
stuff like that, Misato !
I...I couldn't do anything.
I lost to that
idiotic Shinji.
So frustrating...
Salvage plan for Shinji...?
Yes.  Shinji's life
components still exist.
You respect a human life now ?
We can't lose Shinji now.
I wonder. NERV wants Unit 01 as its puppet, not Shinji's life, right ?
I don't deny that.
We think that Shinji's body lost its cohesion and its particles were freed in the entry plug.
You mean Shinji turned into
particles that we can't see ?
Yes. The LCL components in the plug have been chemically changed...
...and it's very similar to sea water of primitive Earth.
The soup of life...?
All Shinji's components were kept inside the plug, and his soul must be there as well.
In fact, his ego has virtually
created an image of his plug suit.
In short, our salvage is a process to recompose his body and stabilize his soul in it.
Can you do that ?
With Magi's help.
Theoretically speaking, right ?
We won't know until we actually try.
What's that ?
Where am I ?
The entry plug of Unit 01 ?
But no one's there.
I'm not there either.
What's that ?
What's that ? What's that ?
I don't get it.
People...They're the people I know
and the people who know me.
That's right.
They're all in my own world.
What's that ?
It's supposed to be in my world,
but I don't understand.
An image from outside...?
A disgusting image...
That's right,
it's my enemy.
Enemy, enemy, enemy, enemy...
They're our enemies that
have the names of Angels.
Eva and NERV's target.
Misato's father's enemy...
Why am I fighting ?
Are you stupid ?
Unknown enemies are attacking us. It's natural to get rid of sparks raining down on us.
I wonder if I don't need a reason.
I wonder if I shouldn't think about it.
Enemy, enemy, enemy, enemy.
They're all enemies.
Someone who threatens me and us,
in other words, the enemy.
What's wrong with defending
ourselves with our own hands ?
Enemy, enemy, enemy,
enemy, my enemy...
My enemy...!
Damn, damn, damn...
You hurt Touji
and killed Mother !
Father...
Why do you
hate your father ?
It's natural.
A father like him...
Don't you understand your father ?
Of course not, because
I haven't seen him very often.
Is that why you
hate your father ?
Yes. He doesn't need me.
He deserted me.
Am I a substitute for you ?
That's right !
You must be !
I was deserted
because you were there !
You ran away yourself.
Shut up, shut up, shut up !
It was all Father's fault !
I was going to say,
``I hate you'' at that time, but...
Are you saying that I have to pilot that and frighten myself...?
That's right.
Why ?
I don't want to !
Why now ?
I thought you didn't need me !
I called you
because I need you.
Why me ?
Because no one else can.
I can't. I can't do it because I haven't seen or heard anything about it !
No. I knew it.
I knew Eva...
...and I ran away from Father
and Mother at that moment.
NEON GENESIS
Currently, the LCL temperature
is being maintained at 36.
No problem in
oxygen density.
Radial electromagnetic pulse, nominal. Wave pattern, B.
All equipment working normally.
You completed the outline of the salvage plan in a month. It's just like you.
Unfortunately, the original idea's not mine. This is experimental data from 10 years ago.
Did it happen during Eva's development, 10 years ago ?
It was long before
I arrived here.
My mother seemed to be observing,
but I only know the data.
What was the
result that time ?
They failed.
Kind...
...warm...
...is this human warmth ?
I didn't know this.
What's loneliness ?
I didn't know, but I feel like I can understand it now.
What's happiness ?
Does everyone act
kind to you ?
Yes.
Why ?
It's because I'm the Eva pilot.  Because I pilot Eva, they treat me very well.
That's the reason
why I can stay here.
It's everything
I depend upon.
So, I have to pilot Eva.
Then...?
Enemy...I have to fight against what they call the enemy.
I have to win. Yes.
I mustn't be defeated.
I have to pilot Eva as they say, and I have to win as they say.
Otherwise...no one...
...no one...
Good luck.
What're you doing ?
Do it right.
Good luck.
Well done, Shinji.
Misato, Ritsuko, Asuka,
Touji, Kensuke...
...and Father...
They praise me...
They praise me
if I pilot Eva.
Everyone suggests someone like me pilot it. My father does, too.
I'll make my father have
a better opinion of me.
Good luck.
I'm doing well.
I am.
Be kind to me.
I fought well, and I'm
trying to fight so hard !
Treat me well.
Be kind to me !
I'm kind to you.
Say, Shinji...do you
want to join with me ?
Do you want your body and soul to join with mine ?
It's very very comfortable.
It's alright.
I'm ready anytime.
Hey, idiotic Shinji...do you want to join with me ?
Do you want your body and soul to join with mine ?
It's very very comfortable.
I'm asking you.
Come on now.
Ikari...do you want
to join with me ?
Do you want your body and soul to join with mine ?
It's very very comfortable.
Ikari...
Do you want to
join with me ?
Do you want your body and soul to join with mine ?
It's very very comfortable.
Don't worry.
Open your mind.
All inducing rods are inserted.
Electromagnetic wave's fixed to zero minus three.
Psychic essence threshold
pulse has been connected.
Roger.
Start salvage.
Roger. I'm sending
the first signal.
Eva's received the signal.
No rejection occurred.
Start sending the second
and the third signal.
Catechizes normal.
No anomalies
Roger. Move on
to stage two.
Shinji.
Idiotic Shinji.
Hey, Shinji.
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari.
Shinji.
Idiotic Shinji.
Hey, Shinji.
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari...
It's not working.
Psychic threshold's fixed in a loop.
Radiate wave patterns
in every range.
It's no good, the signal's
trapped inside the Cline space.
What do you mean ?
We've failed.
Stop the intervention.
Reverse the tangent graph.
Set adding
parameters to zero.
Okay.
There's an anomalous sign in the old area. Pattern sepia.
There's a change in core pulse !
Plus 0.3, confirmed !
Maintain current status.
Prevent reverse flow.
Okay.
Plus 0.5...0.8. Something's wrong.
I can't stop it.
That's...
Why is it...?
Don't you want
to come back, Shinji ?
I don't know.
I...
What do you want ?
Eva refused the signal !
LCL components
breaking down !
Pressure's rising
inside the plug !
Stop everything !
Shut down the power !
It's not working !
The plug's going to eject !
Shinji...!
Where am I ?
Inside Eva.
Inside Eva...?
Did I pilot Eva again ?
Why ?
Don't you want
to pilot Eva ?
I decided not
to pilot Eva.
But you piloted
Evangelion Unit 01 again.
Shinji, you're here
because you pilot Eva.
Because you piloted Eva,
you became as you are now.
You can't deny the fact that you piloted Eva, nor your present or past self.
You should decide what you're going to do from this moment on.
I...
Only one person...we couldn't even save one person. What is science for ?
Give Shinji back.
Give him back !
Smell...the smell of a human...?
Misato...?
Ayanami...?
No, it's not.
That's right.
It's the smell of Mother.
He has to live after the Second Impact, doesn't he ?~~In this hell...
If he wants to survive,
anywhere could be like Heaven.
He has a chance to be happy anytime because he's alive.
I see.
You're right.
Mother...
Have you decided ?
Shinji for a boy
and Rei for a girl.
Shinji, Rei...
Mother...
Shinji !
The repair work for Unit 01 will be done by the day after tomorrow.
Humans use the power of God as a tool after all.
I don't know. The committee has proposed restraining it.
Artificial humanoid Evangelion...
The unknown black box seems too large for a thing humans created, don't you think ?
Well, Shinji was saved
in the end, so it's okay.
I didn't do it.
It was probably
because of you.
How about a drink ?
It's been a while, right ?
Sorry, but I have
something to do.
I see.
Bye.
As soon as Shinji's safety is confirmed,
she's off to meet a guy.
I shouldn't talk.
Ritsuko probably despises me and thinks that I'm an indecent woman.
It's more realistic to be addicted to desire as a human. I can be deceitful then.
Deceive our intelligence,
Commander Ikari or Ritsuko ?
Or me ?
No.~~Myself.
Someone else, right ?
You're not interested in others,
but you hate loneliness.
You're just
like my father.
You still smoke ?
I only smoke after things like this.
So you're the only one who knows.
I'm honored.
So, how far has the
Human Complement Project progressed ?
Why is Adam, which might destroy humanity, kept underground ?
You're meeting me
to find that out.
Honestly speaking,
that's part of the reason.
I'm happy to be used by a woman, but I can't tell you in a place like this.
It's alright as long as I can make you understand how I feel.
What's NERV and
Commander Ikari's true purpose ?
That's what I want to know.
Hey, you can't avoid
the subject by doing this.
No. Don't put
strange stuff in.
At a time like this...
what's that ?
It's a present
after eight years.
It could be the last...
TO BE CONTINUED
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Dave
Brain
Barbara
The Doctor
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
Version 1.0
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara~
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
~Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Kihl: Mugito~~~~~~
Preview
Vice-Commander Fuyutsuki has been abducted by SEELE.
The memories form the present as others delve into NERV.
Could NERV really be a fortress for all Mankind?
Next time,
``NERV Arises''