Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.
Young boy, become a legend.
Neon Genesis
Katsuragi, it's me.
I'm sure you're listening to this message,
after I caused you so much trouble.
Sorry.
Please tell Rit-chan "I'm sorry".
And there's one more thing to trouble
you with.  I've been growing flowers.
I'd appreciate it if you
could water them for me.
Shinji-kun knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Don't hesitate.  Move ahead.
If I can see you again, I'll say the
words that I couldn't say 8 years ago.
Bye.
A telephone that doesn't ring...
ON BUSINESS
Sorry, but don't
call me
Misato-san's shutting herself
up today, as usual.
Authorized Personnel ONLY
If you enter without my
permission, you shall die!
Entry Forbidden!
Asuka...  she isn't coming back today?
She doesn't go to school or home,
she just plays games all day.
Hikari...
Hmm, what?
Let's go to bed.
Yeah.
Sorry, I'm inconveniencing you.
No, you're not.
I didn't win with Eva.
I lost all my values for everything.
I hate...  I really hate...  I hate everything.
Though I hate myself the most.
Now I don't care about anything.
I have nothing to do.
I think you can do anything you want to.
I don't blame you.
I really think you've done well.
Well, that child is gone.
Hmm, probably.
Even cats die.
Don't cry, Grandma.
Mm, I'll come home when I have time to.
I haven't been to my mom's
grave in three years.
Next time, I'll call you.
OK, I have to go.
So, that cat died.
Episode 23'
TEARS
It's impossible for us to
retrieve the Lance of Longinus.
Why did you use it?
And about the Eva series, we
don't have all of them scheduled.
The annihilation of the Angel was more
important.  There was no other way.
No other way?  Your excuses
should be more persuasive.
The things you have done recently are too bold.
Fuyutsuki, I'm in a conference.
Understood.
An Angel is approaching right now.
We'll finish this discussion
at the next opportunity.
That is, if your chair remains.
Ikari, are you going to betray Seele?
I'll be there in 15 minutes.
Launch Unit 00 from the 32nd gate.
Set Unit 02 as backup.
No, I don't have the right to cancel
Commander Ikari's freeze on Unit 01.  Bye.
Angel confirmed visually...  right?
Unit 00, move out!  To the intercept position.
Unit 02, wait at your present position.
No, sortie.
Commander!
I don't care.  At least it
might be useful as a decoy.
Yes, sir.
Eva Unit 02, be ready to sortie.
I'm on board again, as usual.
Oh, no.  Am I still attached to this?
Unit 02, to the 8th gate.
Move out, as soon as the
launch position is determined.
Even if I sortie, all I can do is disturb the others.
Target approaching.  Passing by
the final defense line at Goura.
I don't care about anything, anymore.
Target floating above Owaku Valley.
Rotating at a fixed position.
Target's AT Field is still active.
Where have you been?
I don't have an excuse.
Present status?
Still a stalemate.
Changing cyclically from pattern blue to orange.
What does that mean?
The Magi indicate that it's impossible to tell.
The data is insufficient to find an answer.
But I'm sure that shape isn't fixed.
Our side can't attack first.
Rei, we'll observe its status for a while.
No, it's coming.
Rei, prepare for battle!
No!  It's too late!
Target has physically contacted Unit 00.
Unit 00's AT Field?
Developing, but being penetrated.
The Angel is trying to achieve
first level contact with Unit 00?
Danger!  Unit 00's bioparts are being penetrated.
Eva Unit 02, sortie!  Have her
rescue Rei and provide cover.
Progressing, and penetrating further.
This is dangerous.  5% has
already been bio-fused.
Asuka, advance 300 meters and
develop an AT Field, then fire the
palette gun at the Target's back.
Alright?  Eva Unit 02, lift off!
Move out!  Asuka?!  What's wrong?
Unit 02's status?
Impossible.  Synchro ratio is under 10%.
Asuka!
...doesn't move.  It doesn't move.
Like this, she'll be a victim too.
Retrieve her!  Hurry!
Who?  Me?  Me within Eva?
No, I feel someone else other than me.
Who are you?  An Angel?
The being that we call an Angel?
Don't you want to be unified with me?
No.  I am I.  Not you.
Hmm, but you shall be.  It's too late.
I give you part of my mind.
I give you this emotion.
Pain...  See, your mind has pain.
Pain?  No, something different.
Loneliness.  Yes, loneliness.
Loneliness?  I don't understand.
Do you hate being alone?
We are many, though you hate being alone.
That's called loneliness.
That's your mind.  Full of sadness.
That's your own mind.
These are tears.
It's me who's crying.
Rei!
The freeze on Unit 01 is
canceled, effective immediately.
Sortie as soon as possible.
Sortie!
Yes, sir!
What's this?  Last time, he wouldn't use that for me.
Develop your AT Field and rescue Rei!  Quickly!
Yes, ma'am!
Ikari-kun!
Shinji-kun, use your prog knife!
It hurts, doesn't it Ikari-kun?
Is this my heart?  To be one with Ikari-kun?
No.
AT Field reversed.  Penetrated instantly!
To hold the Angel?
Field limit reached!  The core
can't hold up much longer!
Rei!  Abandon the unit and escape!
No.  If I escape, the AT
Field will disappear.
So I won't.
Rei, do you want to die?
The core is collapsing, passing
through the critical point.
The target has disappeared.
This operation is finished.
Move to level one alert.
Roger.  Moving to situation yellow immediately.
Unit 00's status?
Entry plug ejection not recognized.
Rescue the survivor.  Hurry!
You mean, if there is one.
Still unable to find the constituent matter for
section 16.  Location efforts proceeding.
...extending in the southwest direction.
Dr. Akagi...
This is top secret.  Scavenge the plug.
Dispose of the parts concerned.
Roger.
Do it immediately.
The 3rd Angel
Sachiel
The 4th Angel
At last we have defeated
the Angels, up to the 16th.
Shamshiel
The 5th Angel
Ramiel
The 6th Angel
Gahgiel
The 7th Angel
Israphel
The 8th Angel
Now there is only one Angel left, which is
described in the Dead Sea Scrolls of Seele.
Sandalphon
The 9th Angel
Matriel
The 10th Angel
Sahquiel
The 11th Angel
Ireul
The 12th Angel
Leriel
The 13th Angel
Bardiel
The 14th Angel
The promised time is close.  The road
has been long, with many casualties.
Zeruel
The 15th Angel
Arael
The 16th Angel
Armisael
Aye.  After losing the Lance of
Longinus, we lost Eva Unit 00.
That's sufficient reason to dismiss Ikari.
He must understand why
we returned Fuyutsuki alive.
A new sacrifice against Ikari is needed.
And the one must know the truth.
Shinji-kun, I'm coming in.
Misato-san, the tears won't come.
I think I'm sad, but tears never come.
Shinji-kun, all I can do for you is this.
Stop it!  No, Misato-san.
I'm very sorry.
Although he must be lonely,
maybe he fears a woman.
No, he fears communication with people.
Pen Pen, come here.
I see, anybody will do.
It's me who's lonely.
Rei...
The product of my despair,
and yet the object of your hope.
I guess it's impossible to forget her.
Yes, hello.  Really?!
Shinji-kun!
Dr. Odani of the First Internal Department...
Dr. Odani, please contact the second
conference room immediately.
Ayanami!
First Neurological Surgery
Third Surgery
2nd Floor
Hospital Ward
Radiation Diagnosis
X-ray Reception
I'm glad, you're alive!
But, my father isn't here?
Thank you.  You saved me.
What?
You saved me, by abandoning Unit 00.
Oh, did I save you?
Yeah.  Don't you remember?
No...  I mean, I don't know.
I think, probably, I'm the third.
Are these tears?
I'm seeing these for the first time, but it
doesn't seem to me to be the first time.
I...  am I crying?
Why...  am I crying?
That's right.  Preserve the present
status for the First Children.
No need to capture.
This applies to the Second and
Third as well.  Just watch them.
Yet, if they find out Rei is alive, Chairman
Kihl and the others will blame us.
I'll present something else to the
old men of Seele.  There's no problem.
We wish to proceed peacefully.
We don't wish you to suffer from insults anymore.
I don't feel any insult.
A strong tempered woman.
It's quite natural for Ikari to keep her close.
However, it was none other than
Ikari-kun who presented you to us.
Rejecting the interrogation of the pilot of Unit 00,
he presented you as her replacement, Dr. Akagi.
I'm Rei's replacement?
ON BUSINESS
Sorry, but don't
call me
The way to the truth which you wanted,
was sent to you by 36 other methods.
But those won't reach you.
The only one guaranteed is this capsule.
It's completely up to you how to use this.
The pass code is our first memory.
Bye.  Take care.
I'm not upset anymore by
the telephone that doesn't ring...
...since I received your mind.
Is Dr. Akagi's disposition acceptable?
Different from Fuyutsuki.
It's better for us to return her.
She rendered remarkable
service to the Eva series.
She should be useful to us for a while.
Aye, for the future of humanity.
Regarding Evangelions, eight of
them are under construction.
Four more are not.
The disappearance of the Third New
Tokyo City will enhance the project.
Hurry with the completion.
The promised day will be that day.
Yes, hello.
Listen to me.  You're free from
the secret service right now.
You can go out immediately.
Ritsuko-san...
No good, without my pass.
I see.  Kaji-kun arranged this?
The secret of this place must
be revealed before my eyes.
Alright.  And this child will see it as well.
Very well.
This looks just like Ayanami's room.
Ayanami Rei's room.  This is
the place where she was born.
In this room?
Yes, her birth place.
Light and water, which make up Rei's
deep mentality, reflect the image of this place.
Dr. Akagi, I didn't come to see this.
I know, Misato.
Eva?
The first one.  A failure.
Disposed of 10 years ago.
A graveyard for Evas.
Nothing but a dumping ground.
This is also the place where
your mother disappeared.
You probably don't remember,
but you were watching it, watching the
moment when your mother disappeared.
Ritsuko!
You say this is the core of the dummy plug?
I'll show you the truth.
Ayanami...  Rei.
What?  Eva's dummy plug is...
Yes.  These are about to be
the core of the dummy system.
This is the factory for manufacturing them.
This is...?
These are dummies.
And nothing but parts for Rei.
Humans found a god, and thus tried to obtain it.
As a result, humanity was punished.
That was 15 years ago.
The god that they found vanished.
However, they tried to revive the god themselves.
It was Adam.  A human was made
from Adam to be close to the god.
That is Eva.
Human?  Is that a human?
Yes, that's a human.
Eva, which originally didn't have
a soul, now has a human soul.
All of these were salvaged.
However the vessel which truly contains
a soul is Rei.  Only she has a soul.
None of the other vessels have a soul.
There was nothing within the room of Gauf.
These Rei-like things here don't have a soul.
Nothing but vessels.
So I'll destroy them, because I hate them.
Do you know what you're doing?!
Yeah, I know.  Destruction.
These are not human, but human-shaped things.
I lost against the THING.  I couldn't win.
When he's in my mind, I can bear any insult.
I don't care about my own body.
But...  but he...  he did...
I knew that.
I'm stupid.  I...  I'm as stupid
as my mother.  So foolish!
You can kill me, if you wish.
I'd be glad if you did.
You're truly stupid if you wish that.
This is the tragedy of people possessed by Eva.
I'm also one of them.
To be continued..
Neon Genesis Evangelion
Episode 23'
Created by: GAiNAX
Subtitled by: deus X anime
http://www.deusxanime.com/
Script version: 1.12
Source:  DVD [KIBA-6]
Translations:
TV scenes - Kentaro Onizuka
(Literal Translation Series Edited by Matthew Opel)
Revised scenes - Bochan_bird
Editing:  deus
Timing:  deus
Special Thanks to Kotus for Sub Station Alpha
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi~
~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~~~~~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki
~~~~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Preview
The city is gone, his friends have left,
and a boy smiles at the heartbroken Shinji.
The boy's breeze-like, embracing smile enchants Shinji.
However, a cruel destiny has been preordained.
Next episode: "The Final Messenger"